Chapter 2: Pareidolia

Ginny had been gaining distance from the Burrow for what felt like an hour. She knew fully well that she was not actually running away from home; she had no means to provide for herself, and she was not in sufficiently serious trouble to justify her family's disowning her. Rather, she was engaging in a tactic she had long ago discovered, where if she pretended to be more distressed by the possibility of discipline than she actually was, and did something rash like run and hide, her mother would feel guilt and compensate by lightening the punishment and reassuring her that she was loved. It was a highly effective strategy that her mother had accidentally conditioned her to use.

Perhaps Ginny had overdone it this time, though. She wasn't even sure how to return home, and night was falling. She was in a strange neighborhood, but still felt a desperate need to get indoors, as wizarding areas saw all kinds of strange creatures appear in the dead of the night. Best case scenario, you meet a tame puffskein who you take home as a pet. Worst case scenario... stray mountain trolls were known to roam the streets far from their natural habitat, and eat little girls. In that unlikely-but-existent worst scenario, or a million other unlikely-but-existent worst scenarios, Ginny would be done for. The recently-constructed Peverell Family Hospital was a wonder of magical engineering and organization, but it couldn't raise the dead, only the near-dead. It was ideally suited for saving those who would otherwise die of the slow-creeping diseases of old age; the fate of accident victims was still largely up to chance. If you were dead before anyone found you, you were no better off now then you were before. (A wiser wizard might see this as a newfound incentive to take as few mortal risks as possible, to maximize his chances of immortality.) Ginny needed shelter, now.

Just ahead, beyond the cul-de-sac at the end of the road, Ginny saw an ancient undetonated Muggle bombshell, lodged in the middle of a wizard's garden. Past the garden, an enormous grave marker. Past that, a house she thought resembled an enormous statue of a horse's head.

"Oh, no," muttered Ginny, as she knew that this would be the house where she waited for her mother to find her. She could at least reassure herself that if they were serial killers, someone probably would have found out by now, unless everyone just thought it was too obvious. This house had a reputation in the local community; less mature children threw rocks, or rung the doorbell and ran. Simply looking for a place to stay, Ginny simply rung the doorbell and stood there, putting her in the company of less than 1% of the house's visitors. As she waited, she turned around and gazed again at Pandora Lovegood's grave.

"Answer the door, would you, Luna?" called the high voice of a young middle-aged wizard.

"Sure thing, daddy!" called what must be Luna's voice, and then there was a lull, followed by running footsteps. The door opened, and Ginny came face to face with the mythical Luna Lovegood, a girl her same age and height, but with blonde hair bordering on white rather than an earthy red, and much thinner and paler. "Come in."

"I'm sorry to bother you," said Ginny, stepping through the doorway and seeing Luna's father Xenophilius to her immediate left, slouched over in a chair staring intently at some sort of double-sided beetle through a magnifying glass. "I'm just a bit lost, and was looking for someplace to stay while I wait for my mum to find me."

"She'll find you here very soon," said Luna. "I can see it in your eyes." Ginny blinked; she thought she had been avoiding eye contact. "We can wait in my room if you like." Luna offered Ginny her hand; Ginny looked past her at a magically-operated printing press that was pumping out copies of the Quibbler. The headline? "GILDEROY LOCKHART DOES NOT EXIST! A NATION IS DAZZLED BY MASS HALLUCINATION!"

"Alright," said Ginny, though she pointedly ignored Luna's hand, and Luna led her to a spiral staircase, which switched from clockwise to counterclockwise, or vice versa, whenever you stopped paying attention to it. A bit of climbing later, and they were in Luna's room, sitting on the floor.

"I'm Luna Lovegood," said Luna. "You're Ginny Weasley, or else an impostor. I'm very sorry to hear about the incident with Scabbers. You must be very proud of your brother, though, for figuring out the truth about him." Ginny just stared at Luna, uncertain of what to say. "Can I see your hand?"

"Why?" said Ginny, reserved.

"I want to read your palm," said Luna. "I can get at least three good prophecies out of anybody's palm."

"So you're really a Seer?" said Ginny, trying to humor the girl, putting her hand out.

"That's what they tell me," said Luna, already getting to work, holding Ginny's hand with both of hers, carefully examining it. "I've been doing some independent study in divination; the Ministry doesn't even prohibit it- oh, this first prophecy is inappropriate for a young girl to hear!"

"What?" said Ginny, shocked. She had half a mind to take her hand back.

"I'm not even going to say it out loud, sorry," said Luna. "Hopefully the next one's better. Anyway, what was I saying? Oh, yes! The Ministry doesn't even prohibit underage study of Divination, provided that you don't use any other types of magic in the process. I expect to become a much more effective Seer once I can use other types of magic to aid my sight, so I'm excited to finally attend Hogwarts. Right now I can't even block out the Nargles."

"Nargles?" said Ginny.

"You're going to die of magical strangulation," said Luna.

"What?" said Ginny.

"Nargles are magical creatures associated with time," said Luna. "They're always making mischief in the future, which wreaks havoc on Seers trying to do their jobs, and they eat the past after it happens. They're why you can't turn time back more than six hours."

"No," said Ginny, frowning. "What was that about me dying?"

"Of magical strangulation," said Luna. "It says so on your hand." She smiled. "In the play Othello, the Dark Wizard Othello magically strangled his wife to death with a cursed pillow, because she had an affair with another woman. So I think your best bet is to never get married." Luna considered this. "Then maybe you'll live forever!"

"That's... quite a stretch," said Ginny.

"Oh!" said Luna. "And here it says that you'll leave a part of yourself in a secret area of your school, forever. That's almost certainly Salazar Slytherin's Chamber of Secrets. I don't know how you wind up in the Chamber of Secrets, it's been lost for years, and only Slytherins can go in there. Or so the legends say. As for the part of yourself you leave there... I think it's your skeleton. I know a Skeleton Removing Charm that I could learn in a few days if you need any help."

"No, thank you," said Ginny, quickly losing her grasp of what was going on. "I think your interpretations of your prophecies are making some counterproductive leaps of logic."

"Well..." said Luna, dropping Ginny's hand. "It'd be easier to leave a part of yourself in the Chamber if you had a horcrux. But my dad says I can't learn how he made that until I'm seventeen, so it's probably very difficult."

"And how do you know that the secret area is Salazar Slytherin's Chamber of Secrets?" said Ginny. "Hogwarts has hundreds of secret areas."

"It does?" said Luna, delighted. "It'll take ages to get 100% completion, then. That's delightful. Are you sure that you're just entering your first year, too?"

"Yes," said Ginny. "I'll see it for the first time this September."

"We should meet up on the train there," said Luna. "By the way, did you know that the Hogwarts Express isn't a real train? It's actually perfectly still, and enchanted to feel like it's moving. The windows are all just paintings. At the end of the ride they Apparate the entire train to Hogwarts."

"Are you sure?" said Ginny.

"I'm quite certain," said Luna. "Wait a minute. Look into my eyes." Ginny did, and Luna seemed to like it a bit too much. "Completely infested with Eye Fones. I could remove them orally, if you like."

"No thanks," said Ginny, and she scooted away.

"Alright," said Luna, "but you'll need glasses in a few years."

"I'll live," said Ginny.

"Until you get married," said Luna. "Then you'll be magically strangled."

"You came to that conclusion by citing a Marlowe play," said Ginny. "And even then the logical connection wasn't quite clear."

"I'm not sure what you're talking about," said Luna.

"There's a phenomenon called pareidolia," said Ginny. "People look at random data, that cannot possibly have meaning in it, and they draw patterns as if they were actually there instead of just made up in their heads. Shapes in clouds, faces on other planets. All constellations, really."

"Constellations have meaning," said Luna. "Centaurs use them for their type of Divination, which is the most advanced in the world. I'm pretty sure I've heard of types of Divination that use the shapes of clouds, too."

"Hmm," said Ginny, stumped. Perhaps the world made less sense than she thought. "There's a series you should read," she finally said.

"Oh, I love reading!" said Luna.

"It's by Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres," said Ginny. "It's called the Methods of Rationality."

"What's it about?" said Luna.

"It's about how to think," said Ginny.

"Oh, well, I already know that," said Luna. "In fact, I know more ways to think than most people I've met. Watch this." Luna stared into space for a few moments, and Ginny held her breath. "Most random numbers are three," she said. "I bet you've never seen anyone think that way before."

"But how do you know which ways to think are correct?" said Ginny.

"Oh, they all are," said Luna. "I know because they all reach correct conclusions."

"Are you sure?" said Ginny, leaning a bit closer, nervous.

"Are you?" said Luna, leaning a bit closer, putting a hand on Ginny's shoulder.

"Mum!" said Ginny, seeing her mother in the doorway.

"Ginny!" said Molly, more relieved than upset to see her daughter.

"Luna," said Luna, and she crumpled to the ground as Ginny stood up and ran to her mother's arms.

"Thank you for keeping Ginny safe and sound," said Molly.

"You're welcome," said Luna cheerfully. "My mother is dead. Goodbye." Molly blinked twice and took Ginny out of the house, stopping only to thank Xenophilius as well; he gave her a free copy of the latest Quibbler. Immediately outside, Molly took Ginny's arm and used Side-Along Apparition to transport her home to the Burrow.

"Ginevra Weasley," said Molly, unusually, unsettlingly calmly, "what were you doing in my Potions cellar?"

"Getting some peace and quiet," said Ginny.

"Well, you certainly didn't give any of us any peace of mind!" said Molly. "It's dangerous in there!"

"I'm sorry," said Ginny, and she shuffled her feet.

"The Potions cellar is for storage of incredibly powerful and potent substances, often for many years," said Molly. "I can't even remember everything that's in there. If you spilled one on yourself, who knows what would happen?"

"I'm sorry," said Ginny once again, and this time she blushed.

"I'm actually glad you went out," said Molly.

"You are?" said Ginny, in genuine confusion.

"Of course, it's not safe for a girl your age to be out here alone," said Molly, "but you made a friend. That's how I found you; your spoon turned to 'at a friend's house' on the clock."

"It did?" said Ginny.

"That said, never run off and leave us again like that!" said Molly, and she gave her daughter a gentle smack with the Quibbler. "You scared us!"

"I'm leaving for Hogwarts in a few days," said Ginny.

"Yes, and you'll make a lot of friends there," said Molly, and she smiled. "In Gryffindor, I'm assuming?" Ginny rolled her eyes.

"Of course, mum," said Ginny.

"Not a surprise," said Molly. "The entire family has for generations."

"I know," said Ginny. Both mother and daughter came to focus on the Quibbler.

"Gilderoy Lockhart does not exist," Molly read slowly. "I think they must be misinformed. I met him. Very nice man. Very charming. Just talked to him a few days ago, actually. I'm glad he owed me a favor, because the textbook I would have bought four of was expensive as sin. That's why professors shouldn't write their own books, I'd say..."

Chapter 8: Cult-Like Behavior

Ginny was surprised to receive an invitation to Professor Slughorn's newly-reconstituted Slug Club, a social order for those Slughorn believed had special potential; she was a first year Weasley whose most notable academic achievement so far was her performance in her first Defense Against the Dark Arts class. The Weasleys were a proud family, but not particularly prestigious within the magical community; certainly not prestigious enough to help in getting a Slug Club invitation. Ginny was the only first year invited; there were few second years, either, and Slughorn was spending most of his time complaining that one of them hadn't shown up.

"I don't mean to insult any of you," said Professor Slughorn, "but he was the one I was most excited to meet."

"I could bother him about it for you, if you'd like," said Hermione.

"Oh, don't feel obligated," said Professor Slughorn. "...but I really would appreciate it."

"Professor Slughorn?" said Ginny. "I have a private question." The Potions Master smiled and lowered his voice.

"Yes, Ginevra?" said Professor Slughorn.

"Why am I here?" said Ginny. "I don't mean - I mean - I don't really see what separates me from the other first years. I haven't really done much yet. Is it just because you heard about the points I earned from Professor Lockhart?"

"I did hear about that," said Professor Slughorn. He lowered his voice even more, as he was speaking about very confidential matters. "But that wasn't the reason. I was thinking about you, in the aftermath of your little problem. And I realized a very positive secondary – or, I suppose you could say primary – implication of that problem. Have you noticed it?"

"I'm afraid that I haven't, Professor Slughorn," said Ginny.

"Ginny," said Professor Slughorn, "in magical terms, you are a third seventh son." This hit Ginny like several tons of bricks, and she very seriously wondered why she hadn't thought of it before Professor Slughorn pointed it out. Seventh sons, and recursive seventh sons, had no inherent magical properties, but they were the subject of various truly ancient prophecies, particularly third seventh sons. Families that believed in those prophecies, such as the Weasleys, were inclined to have many children in an attempt to attain seventh sons that could potentially be the subjects of those prophecies. According to the ancient definition of the "seventh son" concept, no girls could be born between any of the sons, and so it was easy for a family to get out of the running. Still, it was no surprise that seventh sons should naturally spring up more in the families that believed in the prophecies concerning them, regardless of whether they were true. "Septimus", Ginny's grandfather's name, literally meant "seventh". "Arthur", her father's name, came from a Muggle hero associated with Merlin. As far as Ginny previously understood, the Weasleys had finally run out of luck, at the last possible minute, when she was born. But apparently not, apparently that had only been the obvious interpretation, and not the true one.

"Oh," said Ginny. "I suppose that I am."

"And that, in combination with your unexpected Sorting, strongly suggested to me that you are destined for great things," said Professor Slughorn.

"Thank you," said Ginny, quietly, and Professor Slughorn smiled and nodded. Ginny slipped back into the crowd, and tried to reroute her train of thought to where it had been before. There was no immediate course of action Ginny could think to take, nothing about her current life to reconsider or change, originating from this newfound knowledge of her status as a third seventh son. Therefore, there was no point in letting it consume her. She should return to her previous directive:

"Hey, Draco?" said Ginny; she fumbled for a clipboard with a signup sheet attached to it.

"Yes?" said Draco, more intrigued already than she had expected.

"I'm forming a club for Hogwarts students," said Ginny, "and I wanted to know if you're interested."

"What is it?" said Draco.

"It's sort of a Harry Potter fanclub," said Ginny, "with a special emphasis on studying the Methods of Rationality that he's provided so we can raise our sanity waterline." Ginny had looked at the list of preexisting student clubs a few days prior, and had been surprised to find that no such thing already existed. Well, see a need, fill a need, that's how you get ahead. (More advanced Slytherins alternately use the "make a need, fill a need" formula.)

"Hmm," said Draco. "It sounds very interesting, but I'm afraid I've already met Harry Potter, and spoken to him at length. I haven't read the Methods of Rationality, but from what I've heard, I suspect he's already conveyed the same concepts in conversation with me." Ginny tried not to show her jealousy regarding this. "I suspect Blaise and Tracey would be interested, though, and I wish you good luck."

"Thank you," said Ginny, and Draco gestured farewell and left to mingle. Well, that was disappointing – it was a shame to miss out on someone so close to Harry, but at least he'd been amicable about it. Ginny decided not to ask Hermione – she probably had her own private one-person Harry Potter fanclub already. Soon, Ginny would have her own private network of people who understood her deep personal connection with Harry Potter.

"Is this a cult?" asked Sheila Carrow. Ginny wanted to bury her head in her hands in frustration, but she had too much dignity for that. She was leading over two dozen people, many of them older than herself, people who she had personally convinced to come to this abandoned classroom at this time. She would have to maintain her composure.

"No, and I'm offended by your insinuation," said Ginny.

"I'm sorry," said Sheila. Ginny nodded, and set off some small fireworks her brothers had lent her. None of them were present, despite at least Fred and George expressing admiration for Harry at points in the past; Ginny suspected this had something to do with her being their little sister. Another notable absence was Luna, who, despite her ongoing friendship with Ginny, had declined her invitation to this first meeting; although at least she had said that this was because she needed to catch up with the Methods of Rationality before attending any meetings.

"The first meeting of the Harry Potter fanclub is now in session," said Ginny. She scanned the room; the club's members were mostly from the first three years, though, to her dismay, Lesath Lestrange had also chosen to come to the meeting. Whether this was a result of his unusual interest in Harry Potter or something more sinister was anybody's guess. His presence was balanced out by Cedric Diggory, another older boy who was better-regarded. "To start out, who here has read the Methods of Rationality?" About half of those attending raised their hands. "Alright. Anyone who hasn't should by the next meeting, or at least start. They're a really quick read; you won't have any trouble getting through them."

"What are the Methods of Rationality?" asked Colin, right on script.

"I'm glad you asked," said Ginny. "The Methods of Rationality are Harry's newsletter, except, instead of covering current events, he covers techniques for how he thinks, and how we can think, if we try. How to think rationally, how to be less wrong. There's a new installment every Friday. His mission is to try to make wizards smarter on average, and given that he's Harry Potter, I think he's going to succeed, and we're going to have to keep up or else be left behind."

"What if it's a trick," said a first year Gryffindor named Karissa, "and he's trying to make us dumber so he'll have an easier time taking over the world?"

"That's an interesting hypothesis," said Ginny, "but you don't need to take Harry's tips on faith. They work through pure reason. If the Methods of Rationality told us to think in a way that didn't make sense, that would be blatantly out of line with the rest of it. Thank you for the question."

"If all of us are smarter, won't Harry have a harder time leading us?" said Lesath. "I don't want to be so stupid that I fail him, but I wouldn't want to be smart enough that I could accidentally unravel one of his plots." Ginny wasn't sure how to take this.

"Um, I'm pretty sure that's not how Harry would want you to think," said Ginny. "Read the Methods. Now, let's talk club structure. We are meeting on a weekly basis, on Mondays. My current plan is that I, Ginny Weasley, will be the Club President, and my assistant, Colin Creevey, will be the Club Vice President."

"Doesn't 'president' mean that you're elected?" said Tracey.

"Are we going to vote on this?" said Blaise.

"No!" said Ginny. A pause. "Um, maybe later if there's interest in an election we can hold one."

"I'm running for Club President!" said Blaise.

"What's the third Method of Rationality?" said Ginny. Silence. "I thought so. So. What would Harry want us to do with our time at our fanclub meeting?"

"Discuss current events, and the grievous issues facing the wizarding world?" said Colin.

"That's a good idea!" said Ginny. "What are some problems out there terrorizing the world that you think need solutions?"

"Blood purists?" suggested Penelope.

"A bit inflammatory," said Ginny. "But yes, true, absolutely. Blood purism is fundamentally irrational because I doesn't match the evidence, and on top of that it's a hate movement, which is a generally bad thing to associate yourself with. Interbreeding with Muggles and Muggle-borns consistently has no effect on strength of magic; a better explanation for the slow decline of some aspects of magic is the Interdict of Merlin, which hopefully won't continue to weaken us thanks to the rise of modern communication infrastructures. I'm not sure if blood purism is really the kind of problem we can look for a solution to, though. It probably would have faded out on its own if not for the actions of Voldemort, who is finally well and truly gone, though at great cost. My condolences to all present whose loved ones died at his hands. Any other problems facing the wizarding world today?"

"Our government kind of sucks," said Tracey.

"Bureaucratic inefficiency!" said Ginny. "A truly ancient problem that Muggles have had little more success fighting than ourselves. Any suggestions on how we could reform the Ministry of Magic to be more operational?" A pause, as people thought.

"I can't think of anything," said Tracey.

"Try to think for at least five minutes before you tell me that," said Ginny.

"What if we started an intergovernmental body that slowly overtook and replaced all of the world's magical governments, including the Ministry of Magic?" said Blaise.

"That would probably just make things worse," said Tracey.

"We should try to fix the system from within," said Cho. "Vote in officials who are saner than the current average until everything improves."

"Literally everybody has been trying that forever," said Tracey.

"That's a good point, Tracey," said Ginny. "We're far from the first people to think of this problem, so we shouldn't expect to come up with a working solution in an afternoon."

"No," said Tracey. "I mean, we should try to fix the system from outside. Start a violent revolution."

"That sounds like fun," said Colin, and Ginny shot him a look.

"I heard Hermione has a phoenix," said Flora.

"She's probably going to be the next Minister of Magic," said Hestia.

"I've never seen her with a phoenix," said Ginny, skeptical and hoping to reroute the conversation to Harry-Potter-related matters.

"It's true," said Cho. "She tries not to appear with it in public but she shows it off all the time in the Ravenclaw Common Room."

"They say that's how she wiped out Azkaban," said Flora.

"Azkaban was decommissioned by the Ministry of Magic and replaced with the Azkaban Memorial Museum," said Ginny.

"Oh, so you believe the official story?" said Hestia.

"I thought one of the Methods of Rationality was to doubt everything," said Flora. Ginny screamed, and then clapped her hand over her mouth.

After the disaster that had been the first meeting, Ginny didn't want to go on, and was considering disbanding the Harry Potter fanclub as soon as possible. She very well might have, had Harry Potter himself not made a surprise appearance at the second meeting.

"I heard you started a fanclub?" said Harry. He was a few minutes early, though most of the members were already there, milling about, waiting for the meeting to start.

"Yes," said Ginny, and blushed. Harry Potter was talking to her. Harry Potter. This was what she had always wanted. This was literally the best case scenario of starting a Harry Potter fanclub, which she had quickly dismissed as unlikely.

"I'm interested to see what you put together," said Harry.

"I'm the Club President, and Colin's the Club Vice President," said Ginny. "We're studying the Methods of Rationality."

"Oh! Harry!" said Sheila, cutting in. "I'm so glad to see you. I have a question that I've desperately been meaning to ask you."

"Yes?" said Harry. Sheila shielded her mouth and lowered her voice.

"Is this a cult?" asked Sheila. Harry got the most baffled look on his face.

"What?" said Harry. "No, of course not." An awkward silence. "Um, Ginny, could you excuse me for a moment?"

"Of course," said Ginny. Harry left the room, and Ginny suspected that she heard barely-contained laughter as he did. "Sheila! What have you done? You drove Harry off!"

"I'm sorry," said Sheila. "I'm just really afraid of joining a cult. I trust you and I trust Harry, but you can never be too careful, right?" Ginny wanted to push the matter further, but, to her delight and surprise, Harry was already back, and dragging a large chest with him.

"Hey, you wouldn't mind if I took over this club, would you?" said Harry.

"Of course not!" said Ginny.

"Alright," said Harry. "Then I'm the Club President, now, and you're the Club Vice President."

"What about me?" said Colin. Harry pondered this.

"You can be the Club Secretary of State," said Harry.

"What's that?" asked Ginny, gesturing to Harry's chest.

"A chest full of Muggle clothes," said Harry, opening it to reveal dozens of identical tee-shirts and pairs of jeans. "The Methods of Rationality are Muggle thinking techniques, so it's only fitting that you should wear Muggle garments while studying them to get in the right spirit."

"That makes sense," said Ginny. At this point, Luna entered the room.

"Hi, Ginny!" said Luna, ignoring Harry. "I'm sorry I didn't get here earlier. I had a problem with a Faldron-"

"What's that?" said Ginny.

"A Faldron," said Luna. "It's a little creature that takes up residence in your cauldron, and then it's just about impossible to get rid of."

"I've never heard of a Faldron," said Blaise.

"That doesn't mean it doesn't exist," said Luna.

"Read the Methods," said Blaise. Luna just stared at him.

"Here are your tee-shirt and jeans," said Harry. "Change into them before the meeting starts."

"Alright," said Luna, taking them from him, thinking little of it, leaving the room alongside several other girls. When Ginny got back, the room looked very different. Harry had removed the room's normal lighting and replaced it with candles; the room was much dimmer, now. Flora and Hestia Carrow were standing side-by-side across from the door, holding hands, humming rhythmically in a low register, wearing their new clothes. Harry had also removed all of the room's furniture, and was directing everyone to sit in a circle on the floor.

"Greetings, my young apprentices," said Harry, when he was satisfied that everyone had changed. He was standing above Lesath, who looked particularly funny in his ill-fitting uniform. "I am the new President of the Harry Potter fanclub, or, as it shall now be known, the More Sane Squad, because we have used our arcane knowledge of rationality to become more sane than the rest of the world. I am your instructor and your mentor in all intellectual matters. When I speak, you will respond with 'yes, Harry'. Do you understand?"

"Yes, Harry," mumbled Harry's new ensemble.

"We are the next generation, who will inherit the world," said Harry. "You will all take control much more rapidly than expected, and under my command. You will not always know what is best, and under such circumstances I will inform you of what you want and how to get it. Sometimes, it will be for the best that you question me, but I will tell you when that is the case. Understood?"

"Yes, Harry," said everyone present, except for those who had begun humming with Flora and Hestia, and Luna, who had crossed her arms and looked distinctly unimpressed.

"Lesath Lestrange," said Harry, not even bothering to look down at him, "would you sacrifice part of your magic forever for the advancement of my goals?"

"Yes, Lord," said Lesath.

"Yes, Harry," said Harry.

"Yes, Harry," said Lesath.

"Good," said Harry. "At the conclusion of the meeting, I will have as many of you as possible make Unbreakable Vows of loyalty to me. Given my own status as a Master Rationalist, this will only serve to make you more rational and improve your lives. Do you all find this acceptable?"

"Yes, Harry," murmured the crowd.

"Perfect!" cried Harry, and he began to laugh in a perfect impression of Professor Quirrell. "Do you all revoke all ties to your family, your friends, and your most deeply-held-beliefs, to serve rationality and only rationality, as it manifests before you, as me?"

"Yes, Harry," said the crowd.

"Do you revile cognitive blocks in any form in which they prevent themselves, and will you believe me when I tell you that you are suffering from one, and it needs to be corrected?" asked Harry.

"Yes, Harry," said the crowd.

"Would you give your life at a moment's notice on my orders, whether for such a noble purpose as to save my life, or for such a petty one as to make a point to an enemy?" asked Harry.

"Yes, Harry!" said the crowd.

"I want to see bowing!" shouted Harry. "No, not half-hearted couple-of-muscle bows, full-body bows! I want to see chests on the floor! That's better! Lesath!"

"Yes, Harry!" said Lesath.

"Lead the Squad in a round of 'hail the Dark Lord Harry!'" said Harry.

"Yes, Harry!" said Lesath. "Hail the Dark Lord Harry!"

"Hail the Dark Lord Harry!" said the crowd, now a bit confused.

"You lied!" shouted Sheila, ending the procession. Everyone stared at her. "You lied to me! This is a cult!" The candles all reached a simultaneous end, and the room's regular lighting returned. Harry gestured for the humming to stop.

"Yes," said Harry, "and how long did it take you to figure that out?" Harry stared at Sheila, but she had no answer. He addressed the crowd. "Much of what I've said in the past few minutes was facetious, to teach a lesson, particularly to Sheila, but also to all of you." Ginny was relieved to hear this; on some level she had enjoyed Harry's game but on some level she had been getting worried about how far it would go. "You can't just believe or accept things I say because I say them. I'm just one of you. If I convince you of something, it should be through pure logic and reason, not simply because I declare it to be so. You need to decide things for yourself. And obviously you can't just ask someone if they're starting a cult. If they were, they wouldn't tell you. You need to make observations and derive conclusions from them yourself."

"I'm sorry," said Sheila. "I'm just really afraid of joining a cult. My parents were in one, and it killed them both." Harry was momentarily left completely speechless.

"I'm sorry," said Harry, finally, and in the same moment, Ginny noticed that Luna had slipped out; she was gone.

"Luna!" said Ginny, catching up with her in a hallway looking out on the largest stairwell in the castle.

"How did your cult meeting go?" said Luna. Her voice was acidic in a way few had ever heard it.

"It wasn't actually a cult," said Ginny. "It was just a joke Harry was playing to teach us a lesson. Maybe it was a bit misguided..."

"That sounds an awful lot like an excuse to me," said Luna. "But it explains something. I've been reading the Methods of Rationality, and they're interesting, a bit pretentious at times, but interesting, they have some good points. And Harry, as I understood him from his writing, was acting completely out-of-character just now in that room. So I guess it makes sense that it was all just an act. Of course, it could be his writing that was all just an act. Or maybe both. So how did the rest of the meeting go?"

"Everything just kind of got more and more cultish," said Ginny, "to the point of absurdity, really, until Sheila screamed that she'd been lied to and it was a cult. At which point Harry stopped everything and revealed that it had all been a lesson for Sheila's benefit, to show her that it was stupid and pointless to ask someone if they were starting a cult, because they would lie if they were, and then there was this awkward moment where Sheila revealed that the reason she was so concerned was because she was deathly afraid of winding up like her parents, and then I noticed you were gone. And then the meeting returned to normal, pretty much. Everything from the first part of the meeting was discarded, except for the name 'The More Sane Squad', because Harry really liked that, I guess."

"Goody," said Luna, still dripping with sarcasm.

"And then I decided I had to know where you went and why, so I asked Harry if I could duck out early to find you," said Ginny.

"You went after me?" said Luna, her tone changing on a dime to its usual state. "That's very sweet." She smiled and sat on a nearby bench; Ginny followed suit. "As for why I left... Well... The meeting was exactly what I was worried it would be."

"But you said it was wildly out-of-character," complained Ginny.

"Yes, but only in how quick and obvious it all was," said Luna. "Even if it was all a joke, I still suspect that the More Sane Squad is going to turn into a cult. Gradually and subtly, maybe, but still. Harry thinks he doesn't have to worry about that, because he's caught on to how all religions go, big deadly irrational cults. But he hasn't actually fixed the problem at all, he's just created a 'cognitive blind spot', as he calls it, and his little bubble of ideology is going to balloon like all religions do, into a cult, with followers unquestioningly taking his little kernels of wisdom and worshiping him as an idol or God. Irrationality from rationality. Tragic, really."

"Um, Luna," said Ginny. She had trouble getting this out.

"What is it?" said Luna. "You sound stressed."

"I know Harry doesn't agree with me on this..." said Ginny. She struggled to find the words, and grasped for the fine golden chain around her neck. "But I don't actually think religion is an inherent irrationality. I'm not an agnostic, and I'm certainly not an atheist."

"What are you?" said Luna.

"I'm an Eastern Samothrace Orthodox Wizard Christian," said Ginny. Luna considered this.

"I'm sorry," said Luna, "but that's much more ridiculous than anything I believe. Filled to the brim with internal contradictions. Does 'thou shalt not suffer a witch to live' ring a bell?"

"It only says that in the Muggle Bible," said Ginny, taking on a tone of calm explanation rather than protest. "It's an issue of translation; the word Muggles translate as 'witch' translates more accurately as 'demon-summoner'."

"Alright," said Luna, "but even if God exists, which is an entirely different argument, why on Earth would you think that your specific sect, of all of the hundreds or thousands of competing ones, happens to be the correct one?" Something deep inside Ginny broke at that moment, and it would be long before she realized what that was.

"It's just a set of several different beliefs," said Ginny. "If it turns out that I'm wrong on the most specific ones, which I'm willing to accept as a possibility, then I still have my confidence in the less specific ones, which was already higher anyway. First, I'm a theist, then, I'm a Wizard Christian, then, I'm Eastern Samothrace Orthodox."

"What do you believe, and why do you believe it?" asked Luna.

"As a theist, I believe that the Lord God created the universe," said Ginny.

"Alright," said Luna. "Who is that?"

"The creator of the universe," said Ginny.

"Circular reasoning," said Luna. "Who is that? Go into some level of identifying detail, that separates him from the gods of other religions."
"His name is Yahweh," said Ginny. "He selected the Jews as His chosen people, and led and protected them for many eons. He is omniscient, omnipotent, and omnibenevolent. As a Wizard Christian, I believe that He sent His only son to die for our sins-"

"Define sins," said Luna.

"Ways we fall short of the glory of God, through disobedience," said Ginny. "Because we're all imperfect, we have all committed sins, and unless those sins are balanced out, none of us can ascend to Heaven. By suffering through the Crucifixion, and three days in Hell before His Resurrection, Jesus Christ, the son of God, atoned for all of our sins and gave us all the gift of eternal life in Heaven."

"Alright," said Luna. "Go on."

"Jesus Christ was also a father," said Ginny. "His wife Mary Magdalene bore his children. While the human aspect provided by Mary Magdalene meant that His children lacked the perfect intelligence and morality of God, they possessed some small fraction of His power, and those children became the first wizards."

"I'm sorry," said Luna, "but that's blatantly counterfactual. We have plenty of records and even magical artifacts predating Christ, for example from ancient Egypt. Wizards are descended from Atlantis, not from Jesus."

"Atlantis was lost to time," said Ginny. "We have no idea when it was founded or when it was destroyed. It's even possible that it hasn't been founded yet; the fallout from the destruction of Atlantis violated the Time-Turner rules of time travel and-"

"Complexity penalty," said Luna. "You'd need to find some way to travel through time further than six hours without being eaten by Nargles."

"There's no such thing as Nargles," said Ginny.

"There's no such thing as God," said Luna. Ginny glared at Luna but did not directly respond to her.

"As an Eastern Samothrace Orthodox Wizard Christian," said Ginny, "I believe that the true church was the one founded in Eastern Samothrace by the converted Muggle Pliny the Younger; it later fell into the control of wizards and was being managed by the Bishop Gregor when, as prophesized, it was ransacked and burnt by invaders." And the third seventh son will rebuild the church and bring wizardkind back to the light, Ginny thought, but didn't say. "The church has never been rebuilt despite several attempts, but Eastern Samothrace Orthodoxy remains the most common sect of Wizard Christianity." Which is dwindling, as the wizarding world is secularizing even faster than the Muggle one, Ginny also thought, but also didn't say.

"A very interesting story," said Luna, "but you skipped the most important question. Why do you believe it?" Ginny tried to say something, but couldn't. "You can't answer me, but you know the answer. It's because it's what your parents believe. If your parents had been Djinn Muslims, you'd have just finished telling me the fascinating story of Djinn Islam. If your parents had been Wizard Buddhists, you'd have just regaled me with the story of Buddha and how his wisdom improves your inherent magical power. And if your parents had been normal like mine, you wouldn't have a story at all and we wouldn't be having this conversation. The More Sane Squad? You're no more sane than I am. I didn't agree with everything in the Methods of Rationality, but at least I understood them."

"Luna," started Ginny, slowly. "You've given me a lot to think about. Do you think you could leave me alone for a while, and then we can talk again?"

"Sure," said Luna, and she stood up. "And you can go on being a Wizard Christian if you like. But if you do, please never bother me about being rational again." Luna left, reconsidered, came back, hugged Ginny, and then actually left.

Chapter 9: Radiocarbon Dating

Ginny heard her name called out in the list of first years assigned to Nazariy Natova's army. She wasn't upset that she hadn't been selected to be a general; in fact she had chosen not to apply this year, both because she felt a need to better settle into Hogwarts before assuming more responsibilities, and because she had hopes of building a reputation and being selected on a more meritorious basis next year. Still, she wondered if she would have been selected, had she applied. Ginny didn't know either of the other first year generals.

Harry, of course, was not selected either; he had been a general in his first year and therefore could not be one again until his third year. Rather more distressing was the fact that Ron was a second year general, and Ginny just knew she wouldn't hear the end of it from him. The other two second year generals were Blaise Zabini and Neville Longbottom, one a Slytherin Ginny was close to, and the other a known associate of Harry Potter. Here came Ron now, as full of himself as Ginny had ever seen him (though it was still nothing compared to Percy at literally any second of his life).

"Hey, Ginny!" said Ron. "Sorry you didn't get picked. But better luck next year, right?"

"Actually, I didn't apply this year," said Ginny.

"Sure," said Ron.

"But congratulationss," said Ginny.

"What was that?" said Ron. "Speak up."

"Congratulationss," said Ginny.

"Oh," said Ron. "Thanks." Hmm. So mum was at least wrong about Ron; she supposed that her mother had no real way to know which of her sons were Parselmouths, seeing as she wasn't one herself and it wasn't as if they were all tested for such a thing. Still, Ron didn't seem to be a full Parselmouth; he hadn't understood Ginny until she spoke very slowly. It was as if she was speaking in English to a very slow person. Ginny wondered when, if ever, would be an appropriate time to tell Ron about this gift they shared (but that she had gotten the better end of).

"Ginny!" said Professor Lockhart, who had been watching the proceedings and swooped in to comment. "I'm surprised you didn't apply for the position of general."

"Yeah, I just didn't think it was for me this year," said Ginny. "But how did you know?"

"Because you would have been chosen," said Professor Lockhart. He gave her a mysterious look, and then left. Draco was approaching Ginny very quickly, and she felt very popular.

"Ginny, hi," said Draco. "I was wondering if you'd be up for lunch tomorrow. I have a private room in the Slytherin dormitories." He looked very embarrassed, as if that wasn't how he intended his words to come out at all.

"Um, sure," said Ginny.

"That's great," said Draco, and he hurried away. What on Earth had just happened? Did Draco Malfoy just ask her out on a date? And had she just accepted? Well, given the situation, her choice was probably the rational one. She might never get a chance with Harry Potter, and if Draco was just going to walk into her like this... Well, he was wealthy, and attractive, and kind, and within her age range... and friends with Harry Potter... kind of... He was quite a catch, and just imagining the look on her mother's face was worth the price of admission.

"Ginny!" said Luna, approaching and making Ginny feel marginally less popular. "I'm so glad we're in the same army." Ginny hadn't even noticed. "I'm not sure if I would have been able to cast attack spells at you."

"Thanks," said Ginny, and smiled. "I'm looking for some advice as a friend."

"Oh, I'm always willing to give friendly advice!" said Luna.

"What would you do if Draco Malfoy asked you out on a date?" said Ginny.

"Oh, first Harry Potter and now this?" said Luna. "You're crazy. What's so great about Draco Malfoy?"

"Wealthy, attractive, kind, within my age range, and friends with Harry Potter, kind of," said Ginny. "Also from my House, and emotionally needy, and I'm just thinking of more and more pros the longer I think."

"But he's a boy," said Luna.

"I guess you're not old enough to understand," said Ginny.

"How's the religious soul-searching going?" asked Luna.

"Thank you for reminding me," said Ginny. "I've been distracted." The truth was that she had deliberately avoided thinking about it, to simplify her life.

"Let me know how it goes," said Luna. "The best case scenario is you come out of it as a more sane and functional human being, but I'd be fascinated if you turned out as something interesting like a Latter-Day Satanist or a Triple Jew. Toodles." And with that, Luna skipped off.

Ginny was sitting on a stone bench within the Slytherin Common Room, looking at the entrance, when Dobby appeared before her.

"Master Malfoy will be with you very shortly," said Dobby.

"Thank you," said Ginny, but Dobby had already vanished again. Ginny decided to let her mind wander in the last few moments before her date. This recent incident with Luna and, indirectly, Harry, was far from the first time Ginny's faith had been challenged. Several years ago, while exploring the area around Ottery St. Catchpole, Ginny had met Pansy Parkinson, who had informed her that Weasleys were stupid because they believed that the world was only six thousand years old. Ginny had informed her that the world really was only six thousand years old, and you could determine this from the ages and lineages of the figures in Genesis, right back to the week-long creation of the universe by God.

But when Ginny got home, and began to do research so that she would have a more detailed retort the next time she encountered Pansy, she discovered that her position was well and truly discredited. The Well of Time in the Department of Mysteries was at least a million years deep, and the Unspeakables had barely scratched its surface with no end in sight. Muggles had found the same result from many different sources of evidence, and had even put an approximate objective date on the creation of the universe – fourteen billion years ago, not six thousand. Ginny asked around her family and discovered that even most of them were not Biblical literalists, and had made way for progress and reality.

So Ginny reminded herself that the Bible was not the word of God, but a set of historical documents written independently by different people in different places and different times about God, and that there was no reason to believe an old Jewish creation myth as opposed to objective truth, particularly when it had never been fundamental to her belief in the first place. The evidence could not have been planted as a test of faith; an omnibenevolent God would not resemble an abusive husband asking his wife if she believed him or her own lying eyes. The only way the world could look how it did with a literally true Genesis was if the evidence had been faked by a vast Satanic conspiracy to promote atheism, and believing that was conspiracy theory, the path to the nuttery of survivalist bunkerers or the Quibbler. So Ginny studied evolution, the mechanism the Muggles had determined really brought life on Earth about, and when she came to a true understanding of how it functioned, she realized that it was as beautiful and elegant as the night sky, and she became certain that it was the tool God had used to shape the multitudes of forms of life. You cannot have true faith in something you know to be false – which brought Ginny to her real dilemma.

The world around Ginny looked exactly like a godless world would, so how could she go on holding her theist position? But what did that mean? In what way, exactly, did the world resemble a godless one? All of the things Ginny took as signs of God were there, in the world – but that's just it, they were things Ginny took as signs, and the godless explanation was simpler. Wizards existed, just as Ginny would expect in a world where some were descendants of Jesus Christ – but this could just as easily be seen as a retroactive explanation for where Atlantis came from; it was possible that Christ was a descendant of Atlantis, as all wizards were, and this was reinterpreted later by Wizard Christians with the opposite causality. The Bible existed, as Ginny expected it would in a world where God had intervened in ancient events – but it could just as easily and, in fact, more easily be a collection of myths and lies, none any more true than the opening of Genesis. Ginny was aware of the concept of memeplexes, and the process through which cults developed into religions – she had used it to dismiss many competing religions. She had simply decided that it didn't apply to hers, that hers was true and truly originated from a source meaningful to the inner workings of the universe. But what if that wasn't true? Was there any particular reason to believe that it was? God didn't regularly come down and talk to people and make His existence as clear as that of the sun or the moon. Any sane theist knew that prayer was just a fancy mode of talking to yourself. You weren't interacting with God; you were interacting with your mind's simulation of God. God's existence was debatable, and that itself was an indescribably large blow to the theist position, because it fit precisely with the atheist interpretation of religion and required excuses from the theist position.

And yet, in spite of these simple realizations, Ginny was not particularly less theist than she had been before. She still expected to meet God in Heaven upon her death. She still expected that, if she were to look back at distantly passed times, the history would match up with the basic narrative she had acquired from the Bible. And she still expected that if she pulled out of reality and saw everything in a truly objective way, then above it all, in some higher plane, there would be God, watching everything just like her, and smiling, because it was all going according to His plan. Her expectations for tests' results matched up with a narrative diametrically opposed to the one she now identified as rational, so what did that mean? Was Ginny rationally broken, such that her mind could never climb to the heights Harry's could? All of the tests she expected theist results on were tests she could not perform; did that mean that she only believed in her belief in God? Ginny would have liked to think she knew what she believed in, but at the moment, she honestly had no idea what she believed. What a mess.

"Ginny?" said Draco, standing just in front of her. She had been so distracted she hadn't even seen him approach. She stood up.

"Oh! Draco!" said Ginny. "Hello. You were going to show me to your room? Um – to – your – private dormitory?"

"Yes," said Draco. "It's right down this hall; follow me."

"I wish I could afford a private dormitory," said Ginny, walking.

"It was difficult even for us," said Draco. "It was the result of a sizable donation that my father deliberated for quite some time before making. I wouldn't be surprised if you were able to afford it someday, for your children, but that kind of money takes some doing." He stopped at the wooden door that had the word "MALFOY" in golden lettering, and knocked on it in a pattern; it opened itself.

"Wow," said Ginny, upon seeing the interior, and there wasn't much else to say. The bed was nicer than Ginny's bed at home or at school. The table was visibly more expensive than Ginny's house. The room as a whole was the single most intense pocket of luxury Ginny had seen in her eleven years of life. She wanted it.

"So," said Draco, sitting down and gesturing for Ginny's chair to move for her. "How have your first few weeks at Hogwarts been?"

"Enlightening," said Ginny. "Best month of my life so far."

"Are you happy here in Slytherin?" said Draco. Dobby had appeared, seemingly from nowhere, and was setting the table for a casual meal.

"I would have been happy anywhere that wasn't Gryffindor," said Ginny. "Although I'll admit Hufflepuff would have disappointed me. But yes, I think I was Sorted correctly."

"Anywhere but Gryffindor," said Draco. "So I take it you're not a big fan of your older brothers?"

"You have no idea," said Ginny. "You think they're annoying from a distance, try growing up in a tiny house with them."

"I can't even imagine," said Draco. A wave of his hand, and each glass on the table filled with lemonade, seemingly from nowhere.

"What's your second year been like?" said Ginny.

"Lonely," said Draco. Ginny frowned.

"I'm sorry," said Ginny. Angsty. -5 points? +5 points? Gosh, I don't know.

"I mean, ever since, you know, I've felt like I have a lot less friends here," said Draco. "The other Slytherins who went through the same thing, I feel like they think I'm to blame somehow, and the people who aren't, they avoid me like I'm going to snap at them and blame them, or maybe just like they couldn't possibly understand what I've gone through, which maybe they can't, but..."

"You must feel so betrayed," said Ginny. "By the world and by You-Know-Who."

"I'm so sorry," said Draco. "We should talk about something more pleasant."

"Hmm..." said Ginny. "Oh! Did you know that if you talk to Luna Lovegood for too long, you're liable to wind up in a Quibbler?" She fumbled around in her bag and pulled out a magazine, with her face on it: "GINEVRA WEASLEY SECRETLY BETROTHED TO LUNA LOVEGOOD" - and, in smaller print: "(NOT DRACO MALFOY, SOURCES SAY)".

"I made the mistake of meeting her about a year ago," said Draco. "The next week I discovered that I was pregnant with Harry Potter's baby." Ginny tried to restrain her laughter to an appropriate level.

"Luna's a nice girl," said Ginny. "Just... odd." Come to think of it, Draco looked rather like a male version of her; but then many of the pureblood families looked similar.

"That reminds me," said Draco. "Potter was particularly interested to meet her last year. You should introduce them."

"I'm afraid they've gotten off on the wrong foot," said Ginny.

"Oh, they've already met?" said Draco. "I didn't hear; what happened?"

"Well, not exactly met," said Ginny. "It's complicated."

"I'd love to hear the story," said Draco. At that point, food arrived, and it defied description.

"Well," said Draco, who had just finished his plate. "Do you want my opinion?"

"Of course," said Ginny, and she smiled.

"She could have expressed it in a more sensitive way," said Draco, "but I agree with her on Potter. I knew Potter and was quite close to him for some time, and his qualities that ultimately made me avoid him were the same qualities that I think make him a likely future Dark Lord. He's brilliant, very charismatic, intense about his ideology, is rapidly learning how people work and how to control them - very Slytherin, actually, you know he was almost sorted here and it was probably some trickery from Dumbledore that changed it at the last minute - and he's just drawn to the Dark Lord archetype by nature, really. That 'game' you said he played with everyone didn't sound very much like a game to me; it sounded more like a different self that he snapped out of, or he decided he was moving too quickly or too obviously. He became the president of his own fanclub and commandeered it for his own purposes, and you just accepted it because you bowed to the qualities of his you admired – his intellect, and so on. None of it's very subtle, and I'm surprised Luna Lovegood of all people is the one to pick up on it."

"That sounds like quite a leap," said Ginny. "Are you sure there isn't some bad blood between you and Harry that's causing you to interpret the situation incorrectly?"

"I'm not aware of any if there is," said Draco. "Potter and I drifted apart quite amicably. I'd like to give you a further warning, though." Ginny frowned, because she thought she was beginning to understand Draco's concerns, though she didn't want to.

"What?" said Ginny.

"I don't believe in God," said Draco, "as I'm sure you know most wizards don't. But Potter is an atheist, and not an atheist like myself, or most of the professors here, or even the Lovegoods. He's a capital-A Atheist, and he believes in Atheism just as strongly as you believe in God. Perhaps even moreso."

"Perhaps even moreso," repeated Ginny, and it was increasingly striking her that the only way Harry could believe something even more strongly than she believed in God would be if he knew it because it was a fact.

"There will come a time when Potter tries to convert you, to make you a little more like him," said Draco. "Because really, that's what he wants in life. To make the entire rest of the world a little more like him. He'll ask you to sacrifice a belief central to your worldview that differs from his own. He will try to trick you into making that sacrifice. Don't let him. Those beliefs are your source of power."

"That which can be destroyed by the truth should be," quoted Ginny. "That's the first Method of Rationality."

"There's an ancient art that I've studied called rhetoric," said Draco. "It was invented by the Dark wizard Gorgias, and it's a very Slytherin school of cunning. Rhetoric is the targeted application of what appears to be pure reason to convince someone of something – anything, whether it actually is true or not. Potter is by far the best rhetorician I've ever encountered; before I met him I was inclined to dismiss the entire practice as Muggle mind games."

"That's troubling," said Ginny. Someone was lying to her here, to use her – but was it Harry, or Draco?

"Indeed," said Draco.

"What do you think of religion," said Ginny, "really?"

"There might be some truth there," said Draco. "I've never found it, but I've never really looked; my father never brought the subject up for me, as is the norm. Of course some religions must be lies, though I don't know which ones. The end goal of any cult of personality is to become a religion, and some succeed. The position of a capital-A-Atheist like Harry is that all religions start that way, but often they prove themselves hypocrites when they found their own cults like the Less Sane Squad. I'm sorry, the More Sane-"

"I still think you're jumping to conclusions, there," said Ginny. "I don't agree with Harry about everything, but I think the Squad is a good idea. Its goals are noble."

"Its stated goals, perhaps," said Draco. Ginny's mind was blown by this dichotomy she had not considered. She stopped to consider where to take the conversation.

"Would you be interested in exploring religion with me?" said Ginny. "Maybe it'd fill that void in your life you've been describing."

"I think I would," said Draco.

"We can start whenever you have free time," said Ginny. "Just Bible readings, with me explaining everything – I'd be your annotations."

"That sounds lovely," said Draco, "and – oh! – it reminds me." Draco reached into unknown space and summoned an ornate box. "This is a gift from me to you."

"Oh – Draco!" said Ginny. "I don't know what to say!" You don't give away powerful Dark artifacts on the first date!

"In this box is a Learning Journal," said Draco. "It has a mind of its own, and when you own it, it's your best friend. It doesn't look like it, but you could think of it as a sort of a pet. But it's very bright – it might remind you of Harry Potter, in that regard. It provides great advice – just in the past few months it's given me tips that have made the world around me a measurably better place. The box was a gift to me from my father; he said to open it when all seemed lost, and it would help me. I did, and it has."

"Draco," said Ginny, "I can't possibly take this from you. It's yours."

"It's been a lifesaver for me for months, but I don't need it anymore," said Draco. "I think it's time for it to touch someone else's life, and I think that person is you."

"Draco," said Ginny, but he slid the box into her hands, and she took it from him.

"Technically, it's against school rules," said Draco. "So you can't go around telling people about it. But from one Slytherin to another, I trust you."

"Thank you," said Ginny. "I should take this back to my room, but it's been wonderful talking to you." She squeezed his hand.

"And you as well," said Draco. "We can meet again some time next Sunday?"

"Certainly!" said Ginny. "Goodbye."

"Goodbye!" said Draco. Had Luna Lovegood seen the box Draco had given Ginny, she might have said that it looked exactly like a box her mother had once owned.

Chapter 14: Blackmail in Game Theory, Pt 3

Ginny had been seething in the middle of the night, when she returned to her bed. Now, several hours had passed, and everyone was waking up around her, and she barely felt any better. The school thought they had tested her for possession, and so the possibility wasn't worth considering, but they hadn't thought that she might have been possessed since. Ginny knew for a fact that she had, though she certainly wasn't going to let that particular detail out. She put on the gloves that she had managed to secure, though she barely trusted the gloves more than she trusted Tim; they were flimsy and had little holes in them she had had to patch up with Spellotape. Note to self: if I continue to keep Tim, try to get higher-quality gloves out of Draco. She picked up Tim's paper abode and placed it in a bag, which she carried out to the Slytherin Common Room.

"Colin!" shouted Ginny, finding him and making her way over to him. "I need something from you again-"

"Everyone to the Great Hall!" said a prefect, for the twenty fifth time this morning. "Headmistress's orders!"

"Um, let's talk as soon as possible," said Ginny.

"Okay," said Colin; he followed Ginny all the way to the Great Hall, though Ginny refused to be pressed for more details.

"I'd prefer to tell you privately," said Ginny. "In an empty room somewhere in the dungeons."

"I know just the place," said Colin, though Ginny was unimpressed; it was not difficult to find unused, unattended rooms in the dungeons, or anywhere in Hogwarts, for that matter. Soon, everyone was sitting at the Great Hall, and it gradually dawned on Ginny what was coming; Headmistress McGonagall was standing at the podium with a grave look on her face. When everyone had settled in, the Headmistress began to speak.

"I am afraid I must be the bearer of terrible news once more," said the Headmistress, and Ginny knew that she had been correct, about why they were all gathered there. "I am sure many, if not most, of you are aware by now that a student has been killed. It is true. Cedric Diggory, a fifth year Hufflepuff and star student, was found petrified last night. The greatest efforts of the worlds' greatest healers could not restore him to life. He is truly lost to us. The Diggorys have requested a public funeral this weekend. All of you knew Cedric, and I expect that many of you will attend."

Ginny scanned the room, and saw that each table was miserable in its own way. The Gryffindors had clearly already caught on to what the Headmistress had thus far not said, that it was murder, and the blood of every one of them was boiling with anger; Ginny wouldn't want them to so much as consider the possibility that she was the Heir of Slytherin. The Hufflepuffs had lost a friend, a peer, one of them, an ideal. The Ravenclaws were pushed into a higher state of grief by the wailing of Cho Chang, who cried as loudly as you could without causing much literal noise. Some of the Ravenclaws – particularly Harry, and even more particularly Hermione – had an aura of guilt about them, as though they were responsible for this for not preventing it from happening. And the Slytherins? The Slytherins were as sad as all of the other Houses put together, in large part because they knew that every single one of them would pay the price for Cedric's death, regardless of their guilt.

"After careful deliberation, we have decided not to close Hogwarts," said the Headmistress, "though all classes will be temporarily suspended until next Tuesday. Before then, you are all permitted, and even encouraged, to visit home via the Floo Network. It is not mandatory, however; Hogwarts will remain fully operational. Because, you see, as most of you have probably already concluded, Cedric Diggory was murdered. His murderer is something Muggles call a 'terrorist', one who enacts violence to cause chaos and disarray, to attract attention to their goals. I cannot possibly imagine a possible reaction that would play better into this terrorist's plans than closing Hogwarts. So Hogwarts will stay open, to demonstrate to the culprit that their bloody quest will prove entirely fruitless."

"Yes, the murder was almost certainly committed using Salazar Slytherin's Chamber of Secrets," said the Headmistress. "No, you should not harass Slytherin House about it. They are not responsible for this, they have quite enough other things to worry about, and I once again cannot imagine an outcome the killer would prefer to a wedge being driven between Slytherin House and the rest of the school."

"You might ask what we are doing to protect you, then, if we are not shutting down the school, and the murderer has not yet been identified or apprehended," said the Headmistress. "That's a fair question, and we do have an answer. We have manufactured safety goggles for every Hogwarts student. Because of the way petrification works, you may still be attacked while wearing these goggles, but you will not be killed, or even permanently harmed; merely taken out of commission for the time it takes to brew a Potion of Reanimation. The safety goggles will be firmly magically affixed to your face at all times. If you feel that this is unnecessary, or too large of an inconvenience for you to bear, then you are free to ask your parents to withdraw you from Hogwarts, but I suspect they will mostly tell you that you don't have your priorities in order."

"In order to identify the murderer," said the Headmistress, "who is as of yet unknown, I ask that you not mistrust each other – again, that is what they would want – but do consider the suspicious behavior of those around you. If someone is acting unusual, out-of-character, or simply Dark, I advise that you report them to me or another staff member immediately. Do not suppress your first suspicions. Reports that do not ultimately lead us closer to the culprit will not be punished, as long as they are made in good faith. We must all act together so that the person responsible for this horrible crime may be identified, so that they may be apprehended and punished.

"And rest assured," said the Headmistress, "the murderer, or murderers, will be identified. They will be apprehended. And they will be punished. Because today, we are all Cedric Diggory, every one of us. Standing up to our foes, standing up to death itself, just to get an education. And that state of things cannot stand. There will be peace, because we will make it." The staff, with the exception of the Headmistress herself, walked out into the crowd, dividing the room into distinct sections, carrying boxes of goggles. "You will now receive your safety equipment from the nearest instructor, and a Charm will be applied to stick them in front of your eyes. If you are visiting relatives, you may request to have the Charm removed when you leave; it will be reapplied on your return. When classes resume, Professor Flitwick will teach all years how to reapply the Charm to yourself, in case it should come undone. When you receive your goggles and Fixture-Fixing Charm, you may return to your dormitories."

"Now put your arm around me like this," said Ginny.

"Um, Ginny?" asked Colin.

"No, this is still part of the magical experiment," said Ginny. "Now, I'm going to use this quill to write in this book-"

"It's that same book again!" said Colin. "Is it causing trouble again? Is this safe?"

"Yes," said Ginny. "That this is safe, I mean. And the experiment is to find out if it's causing trouble. Now, I'm going to use this quill to write in this book a bit; please don't look at what I'm writing, it's private. Then, I'm going to take my gloves off, close the book, and hiss at myself a bit. Then I'm going to drop the book, put my gloves back on, and put the book back in its bag. If at any point I do anything remotely unexpected, that's where you come in; I want you to grab the book out of my hands and throw it across the room. Understood?"

"Understood," said Colin.

"And of course, it goes without saying that this is all very secret and you are not to tell anyone," said Ginny.

"Okay," said Colin.

"Alright," said Ginny. "Let's start." She took out a quill, and began to write:

"Hello, Tim." An uncomfortable lull, and then a response appeared.

"You're wearing gloves."

"Indeed, I am. I wasn't sure if you'd even notice. Trying to possess me, are you?"

"No, of course not." wrote Tim. "I just checked to see if I could. You are a properly paranoid girl, Ginny Weasley."

"Yes, and that is the purpose of this entire conversation. There has been a lethal attack on a Hogwarts student, using the Chamber of Secrets."

"The Chamber of Secrets... There had been a similar attack shortly before I was captured... very upsetting to hear that it's happened again. I know some secrets about the Chamber of Secrets, but none that relate to either attack."

"I'm sure you do. I'd like to ask you some pointed questions in Parseltongue. I've boosted security from our last such encounter."

"Alright. Then I assume you are removing the gloves?" Ginny didn't bother to answer in writing; she simply took her gloves off and felt the foreign presence entering her mind.

"What do you wissh to assk?" Ginny asked herself in hisses, but it was actually, of course, the diary speaking through her. Ginny could feel Colin growing nervous behind her.

"May you causse me to forget thingss ssimply by possssessssing me?"

"No. Regardlessss of the level of control I assssume, you alwayss retain full awarenessss when possssessssed."

"May you remove my memoriess by cassting a reflexxive sspell when possssessssing me?"

"No. Cannot casst reflexxive memory removal sspell. Theoretically I could possssessss ssomeone elsse, and remove your memoriess thuss, but I have done no ssuch thing."

"Then where wass I when sstudent was killed?"

"How iss it that you exxpect me to know? When wass the attack?"

"At night, when I wass ssuppossed to be assleep."

"Then I would ssay you were where you were ssuppossed to be. To the besst of my knowledge, you were not pressent at the sscene, if that iss what iss worrying you."

"Wass I ressponssible?"

"Ssome of your older friendss have conccept-"

"Ansswer me!"

"I am. Ssome of your older friendss have conccept called hero ressponssibility, wherein particularly competent people sshould feel guilt for tragediess, because they did not foressee and prevent them. That iss only way I could imagine your being ressponsible for thiss."

"Were you ressponssible?"

"Builder of chamber iss ressponssible. Thiss iss what he built the chamber for. Infamouss masster wass firsst to fulfill intended purposse of chamber, ass weapon. Learned ssome ssecretss of chamber from him. Whoever is now opening chamber is continuing infamouss masster's work, and if not sstopped, will rule world ussing chamber. I dessire to sstop them."

"I apologize for ssusspecting you. Possssibility that possssessssion victim wass ussed to open chamber was brought up."

"You are not my victim. You are my partner."

"Goodbye."

"Goodbye." Ginny removed her hand freely from the diary – once again, Tim had not exerted overriding control over her, to prevent her from doing so – dropping it and putting her gloves back on.

"So did it go well?" asked Colin.

"Very well," said Ginny; she had put her gloves back on and returned the diary to the bag she was using to transport it. She then indicated for Colin to let her go, and she started for the door with him.

"I mean, I assumed so, since I didn't have to save you," said Colin.

"Uh huh," said Ginny.

"Hey, Ginny, um," said Colin. "I was wondering if maybe, some time, we could, um..."

"Oh!" said Ginny. "Thank you, but I'm already seeing someone, Colin."

"Hey! Harry!" said Ginny, managing to find him by a staircase between matters of official business.

"Oh, hi, Ginny," said Harry. "I didn't know it was you."

"I take it there's no meeting this week?" asked Ginny.

"Indeed," said Harry. "Half of the Squad is either visiting home or dead, and I'm caught up in some business myself."

"What do you think about this whole mess?" asked Ginny.

"It's a mess," said Harry. "Frankly, I'd be shocked if no one else died by the time this is all over. Whoever is opening the Chamber is probably very clever, at least in some ways. They'll find a way to route around the goggles. Of course, I don't mean to imply that they're brilliant – this whole blackmail scheme of theirs is simply not very smart, as far as I can tell. They could kill every boy, girl, and teacher in Hogwarts and it wouldn't make anyone end the Interdict of Merlin."

"Could you see the Interdict of Merlin ending any time soon?" said Ginny.

"It's even less likely after this," said Harry. "Because, you see, now if they ended the Interdict, that would be signaling to whoever's done this that their plan to end it by killing Hogwarts students was a success. It would be signaling to any future Dark Lords following in their footsteps that killing people is a good way to make people pay attention to their agenda. It makes the world a generally worse place. That's the thing about blackmail – if you give into it, then it makes the concept of blackmail a stronger one, which means there's a moral imperative not to give into it."

"That's a shame," said Ginny. "So absolutely nothing good will come of this."

"Indeed," said Harry. "Although I'd hesitate to call the Interdict of Merlin being canceled a good thing. Merlin had some good reasons for putting it in place originally, and I'd be hard-pressed to argue with him."

"Muggles don't have to deal with the Interdict of Merlin in scientific research, and look at all that they've accomplished," said Ginny. "Think about all that you would have accomplished if the Interdict had been removed for you."

"Muggles are more advanced than wizards, yes," said Harry. "But they're also much less stable. There are dozens of Muggle inventions that could end their world, in varying degrees, if misused in the precisely incorrect way. I suspect – no, know – that that problem is even worse with magic. Not to mention, of course, that I don't actually know how you would cancel the Interdict of Merlin. I know some people in very important positions of power relevant to the Interdict of Merlin – Amelia Bones, for instance – and I'm pretty sure none of them know how to cancel it, either. I'm pretty sure nobody does, and that's a good thing."

"Let's agree to disagree," said Ginny.

"That's rather difficult for a true rationalist," said Harry, "because true rationalists will necessarily reach the same conclusion, if they're operating on the same priors using actual rationality. Which reminds me, that you really need to examine some of your beliefs and why you believe them."

"What beliefs?" said Ginny, and she did not like the direction the conversation was taking one bit.

"Come on, Ginny," said Harry. "You literally wear a big sign on your chest that says 'I'm a Christian.'" Ginny looked down, confused, and saw her cross medallion.

"Wizard Christian," said Ginny.

"I know," said Harry. "I researched all of the magical belief systems a long time ago, when I first learned of magic, to see if any of them had any more evidence or sense than the Muggle ones. And sure enough, they didn't. It's exactly the same process, a vicious cycle based on broken thinking..." Harry had long ago learned to say "broken thinking" instead of "magical thinking" if you wanted a wizard to have any idea what you meant.

"I've done research as well," said Ginny, "and not come to the same conclusion."

"Of course not," said Harry. "It takes a lot of effort to fix bad mental habits; rationality isn't easy."

"How much research did you do?" said Ginny.

"Enough," said Harry.

"I'd like to talk to you at length about the evidence," said Ginny. Harry stared at her, and then smiled.

"Well, that at least suggests genuine belief rather than belief in belief, so that's a good sign," said Harry. "Perhaps we could meet somewhere in the dungeons – outside the Slytherin dorms, of course – next weekend, after classes resume, and talk. I'm open, then."

"Alright," said Ginny. "I hope to see you there." Harry nodded, strolled off, checked a watch, muttered something vulgar to himself, and stepped out of sight while turning something in his pocket. After a few minutes, Ginny managed to twist things from "some of my most strongly-held beliefs are being challenged by my idol" to "Harry Potter asked me out on a date!"

Chapter 21: Utilitarian Priorities Again

Wolfsbane, Devil's Snare, Venomous Tentacula, Jumanjian Plot Kudzu, Eclipse Ivy, Spiky Ivy, Writhing Ivy, Screechsnaps, Puffapods, Saint Etheldreda's Flytraps, Bubotubers, Ultraviolets, Mandrakes – mostly Mandrakes. The Hogwarts greenhouse was filled to the brim with exotic magical plants, many of which refused to stay silent, ever, and it consequently felt like the busiest and most crowded section of the school, even though, at present, it contained only two members of the animal kingdom - both humans.

Pomona Sprout, the Herbology Professor at Hogwarts, was not having a very good day. The most obvious manifestation of her not-very-good day had been when, during a fourth year Gryffindor class, a student had deigned to spell her name in small flaming letters, and rearrange them into a rude phrase. Pomona hated disrespect, nearly as much as she hated fire (seeing as it was the natural enemy of so many plants). But that incident (which had fortunately at least led to several students receiving detention) had merely been symptomatic of a larger-scale issue, wherein the public knowledge of her unwitting involvement in last year's evil subplot had led the school to see her in a different light – particularly now that new, more blatant evil was afoot, and it was convenient, at least for the sake of a joke, to suggest that she might be a tool of darkness again. She wasn't. Pomona Sprout was perhaps the single person at Hogwarts least involved in an evil plot.

Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres, the Chief Warlock, didn't think he was having a very good day either, though the truth was that his problems were ultimately much less significant than those of Professor Sprout. After more than a year in the wizarding world, he had finally come up with a magical "cheat" that, though not quite an instant path to godhood, was still a damn sight more powerful than anything of its type that had previously existed. Unfortunately, this year was full of distractions: Bellatrix stirring up international crap and continuing to evade capture, Slytherin's Monster causing political drama right around Harry's own home, the Anti-Patronus doing Harry-didn't-even-know-what-but-it-sounded-very-bad... Why was Slytherin's Monster alive, anyway? Hadn't Voldemort heavily implied he'd killed it?

Maybe that was a ruse, just to keep Harry away from the Chamber. Harry had been looking for the Chamber ever since it had become a looming threat to Hogwarts students, but he had had little luck. It had been easy to find secret passageways hidden from the ninety nine percent of Hogwarts students who weren't Parselmouths; in fact, Voldemort had showed him one such passageway last year. But that was just the thing - they were easy to find, they were empty, and they were interconnected; they permeated the school, and were nearly as large. They connected with each other in no coherent way; occasionally there was a dangerous trap, or a cryptic device that certainly did something, but Harry didn't know what that something was. What there wasn't, as far as Harry could tell, was Slytherin's Monster, or a Chamber to contain it. Not that he'd explored enough of the labyrinth to really say that with a firm conviction. Harry had only penetrated the first layer of Slytherin's security, and he knew it.

On top of all of these externalities, there were two inherent problems with Harry's new ascension idea: if the method ceased to be a secret, then murdering Harry suddenly became a much more attractive proposition for the world at large. And once the process was initiated, it would be very difficult not to expose what he had done, at least to those immediately around him. Therefore, it was only really appropriate for either an emergency (akin to The Night Of The Thirty-Seven, though it wouldn't have worked in a circumstance quite that constrained) or an about-to-dominate-the-world-anyway endgame. There was another problem with Harry's idea, but it was a very minor one, and he was working on it at the moment.

"Hello, Professor Sprout," said Harry. She looked up from the Mandrake she was attending to and turned around.

"Oh, hello, Harry," said Professor Sprout.

"Attending to the Mandrakes?" said Harry.

"Yes," said Professor Sprout. "The new batch are in their critical window."

"Ah," said Harry. "For... Felix Felicis, right?"

"Right," said Professor Sprout, and something golden sprayed out of an atomizer in her hand into the pot. Harry silently allowed her to work, speaking up only when she seemed to be at a stopping point.

"I thought that potion was so broken when I heard about it the first time," said Harry.

"Come again?" said Professor Sprout.

"I mean..." said Harry. "I thought my understanding of it was too good to be true. And it was, because I'd misunderstood it."

"As many have," said Professor Sprout.

"It tries to give you what you want, but it doesn't actually know what you want," said Harry. "It's not very smart, and it's not good at modeling the desires of organisms that are."

"Not a problem with Mandrake saplings," said Professor Sprout. "Bless their little hearts. The Felix makes them smarter if you give it to them when they're growing, but they're still just plants."

"And when they're smarter, they're suitable for the Potion of Reanimation," said Harry.

"Precisely, Harry," said Professor Sprout. She didn't generally refer to her students by their first names, but Harry, being who he was, had a different status altogether.

"I can still hear some of them screaming instead of babbling, though," said Harry. The babbling ones actually unnerved Harry more than the screaming ones, because, their vocalizations formed real words and sometimes even phrases. It was probably just a Markov chain, but still...

"Don't remind me," said Professor Sprout. "Those are the ones I failed to properly administer the potion to. Total waste. Perfectly ordinary Mandrakes that are perfectly unsuitable for reviving the petrified. I'll have to put them down before their screams become dangerous to humans. I mean, not that the other ones are surviving either; I'll have to chop them up. And even the smartest Mandrakes scream when they're being killed." The Herbology Professor just laughed, and Harry decided not to model the mental processes that led to the laughter.

"Theoretically, because of how Felix Felicis works, any Mandrake could emerge from their critical window in the state of heightened intelligence," said Harry. "It's just an infinitesimally small chance." Professor Sprout stopped to consider this before accepting that it was essentially correct.

"Yes," said Professor Sprout. "The Felix just ensures it."

"Got it," said Harry. Harry weighed the value of the Mandrakes' lives with the value of his petrified classmates, before recoiling in horror – of course his classmates were more valuable. The Mandrakes were more intelligent than your average plant, but were easily less developed than a variety of animals Harry would've sacrificed to save human lives without even blinking. They were only marginally more ethically significant than an embryo. "I actually had a different question I came here to ask you."

"Ask away," said Professor Sprout.

"How would I purchase industrial quantities of Screechsnap Sap?" said Harry.

"Come again?" said Professor Sprout. "I understand that you want to know about purchasing Screechsnap Sap, correct? But there was something I was missing."

"Industrial quantities?" said Harry, and Professor Sprout seemed puzzled. Harry reminded himself that the concept of "industrial quantities" would be foreign to a wizard; mass-production was a little-known secret among them. "How would I buy it in bulk?"

"I can't imagine what you'd want it for," said Professor Sprout, "but Slug & Jiggers Apothecary is your best bet, seeing as it's a potion ingredient. They might not have as much as you want in stock, depending on how absurd you're currently feeling, but you could always place an order with them. At Hogwarts we harvest our own sap, but we only make as much as we need year-to-year."

"Thank you," said Harry. "That's much more helpful than what Professor Slughorn said." If Professor Slughorn really wanted Harry to join his 'Slug Club', he'd have to do a lot better than answering Harry's questions with "Professor Sprout could probably give you a better answer".

"You're welcome," said Professor Sprout. "Are you going now? I really need to get back to work; this stockpile is critically important for preserving the integrity of Hogwarts' student body. I'm sure Headmistress McGonagall told you as well."

"Indeed she did," said Harry, "and indeed I am. Going. Goodbye!"

"Goodbye," said Professor Sprout. Harry left, walking past a Mandrake that had just discovered a novel proof of the Pythagorean Theorem, a Mandrake wedding, and a heated Mandrake debate on whether humans were an intelligent species or a mysterious force of nature.

BFIM!

A noise that was high and low all at once in pitch, like a bullet ricocheting off of a drum at a near-flat angle, but deafeningly loud, shook Hogwarts' campus in the dark of the night. Accompanying it was a bright white beam of light, about as thick as a dinner plate, which suddenly burst out of the ground near the greenhouse and pierced the heavens. The beam persisted, and it gave off a quieter, but still awful, hum, and many were awoken, but many still decided to try to sleep.

BFIM!

A few moments later, a second, identical noise, alongside a second, identical beam, in a slightly different location. The ambient hum was twice as loud, now, and Headmistress McGonagall had already climbed out of bed and begun to rush downstairs. Her Time-Turner was jammed, a clear sign to her that Time was itself implicated in whatever was happening.

BFIM!

A third beam, and it was now geometrically obvious that the beams thus far assembled formed three of the four corners of a rectangle that would enclose the greenhouse. Harry, too, was now stirred, and his path downstairs would soon merge with Minerva's. Each was occupied with a slew of barely-coherent Patronus messages.

BHUM!

The fourth and final beam knocked everyone down; its volume was not something one could account for. The new ambient noise, too, was far greater than a simple quadrupled form of the first ambient noise phase - for the space between the beams was now filled in with a translucent but distinctly visible field swimming with electric yellow "veins". Anything and anyone in the greenhouse was trapped.

The Headmistress screamed upon seeing Pomona Sprout inside the field, pounding on its perimeter with her fists, pleading unhearable. Still, she rallied all of the staff she had summoned to cast every spell they knew at the strange, unknown enchantment, to hopefully break it. Even Harry was brought in to cast his Patronus. But it could not penetrate the arcane shield, which simply absorbed many general use offensive spells Harry had never even previously heard of. Professor Columbus cast something that formed enormous spherical sponges in mid-air, that drew magic away from constructs around them before vanishing, but it had no visible effect. Worse still, the silhouette in the greenhouse was moving...

It was a figure shrouded in magical smoke; its movements were more like a banshee than a human, and even many professors would later swear it was an Inferius. It projected Fiendfyre from its arms, which grew to consume and melt the greenhouse. And it dragged Pomona Sprout into the blaze, to hasten her end. The Headmistress was running out of breath to scream with, but many others, who were trickling out of the castle to see the commotion up close, were only beginning.

There was a magical burst (slightly muffled, as Harry vaguely recognized) and a sizeable percentage of Hogwarts' student body became able to see Thestrals.

In the mangled wreckage of the greenhouse, the dark figure bent down, obsessively stroked the ashes as if they were its lover, and finally stood. The Fiendfyre had mostly died down, except for a few small pockets immediately to the figure's sides. It mechanically waved at the terrorized crowd, and the flames surged up around it; when they puffed out of existence seconds later, so too had the figure.

About a minute later, the protective field vanished - but there was immediately a muffled explosion that caved in the ground on which the greenhouse had stood, and Professor Flitwick sustained a broken bone. So ended the assault. The scene was roped off and thoroughly analyzed; several things of note were discovered. First, and a foregone conclusion, Professor Sprout's charred body. Second, a series of unusual, unknown magical artifacts - four stone discs that had clearly been used to generate the protective field, and one complex, multicolored widget, towards the center of the scene, with the letters "NB" carved into it but its purpose otherwise unknown. Third, something that the Aurors all nearly missed, but was of great interest to Harry. Fourth, absolutely no plants, none at all - at least none that were alive. Fifth, a message scrawled in the ashes: "YOU WILL BE PERMITTED TO GROW MANDRAKES WHEN THE INTERDICT IS ENDED". (This was foolish, explained the Headmistress, not only because there was no way to end the Interdict of Merlin, but because Hogwarts was obviously not the only site working to prepare Potions of Reanimation.)

Five suspects were investigated. Hermione Granger was investigated first on the basis of her phoenix and its abilities resembling the mysterious figure's disappearance from the area, but it was quickly determined that phoenixes and Fiendfyre were mutually exclusive magical instruments; the same person could not wield both (and, in fact her phoenix was now in hiding as it was now considered vulnerable to attack). Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres identified an artifact at the scene as stolen from the Time Room at the Department of Mysteries, used to prevent Time-Turner-based examination of the attack. Ginny Weasley failed to show up promptly when summoned, but her alibi, that she was using the restroom at the time, and was only vaguely aware that a calamity was occurring, ultimately proved sufficient. Gilderoy Lockhart was detained because he was the Defense Professor, but no one could think of any other reason to suspect him. And Lesath Lestrange, who was not by any means the Heir of Slytherin, was held for questioning, owing largely to unrelated matters, though his location was unaccounted for during the incident. He was suspended from all classes indefinitely, on the request of Miss Tracey Davis. Following the public execution of Pomona Sprout, Lesath Lestrange was the only individual made to suffer consequences.

"And make no mistake about it," said Hermione. "If Hogwarts hadn't needed so badly to punish somebody, then Lesath Lestrange would still be alive."

Chapter 22: The Problem Of Suicide

"I didn't mean-" said Tracey.

"Wizards can't be hanged-" said Colin.

"-with Muggle rope, idiot," said Peregrine.

"That's such an advanced curse, though, where-" said Lavender.

"He's an older Slytherin boy and his mother is Bellatrix Black," said Cho.

"...I'm so sorry..." said Daphne Greengrass.

"Meta Merlin..." said Harry. "I told him that I really regretted having to do this, but he should stop coming to-"

"It's not your fault, Harry," said Hermione.

"Let's see..." said Luna, shuffling some cards, which Ginny distinctly saw go in and out of each other and transform via a magic she didn't know. "The Hanged Man in The Tower... that definitely means that Death is coming."

"Death already came, Luna," said Ginny.

"No," said Luna. "It's still coming. ...I'd better warn everyone."

A student saw Lesath's corpse hanging in the Astronomy Tower before the Hogwarts administration managed to isolate the area to prepare a controlled release of information, so news spread rapidly through the student population. Nothing prevented Professor McGonagall from going back in time six hours to ensure there was no foul play involved, but of course she borrowed Hermione's cloak of invisibility to do it – if she contacted Lesath, she knew, she would be further causally linked to his death than she had to be. No direct evidence of evildoing was found; in fact, Lesath even enchanted the rope to hang a wizard himself.

Lesath left a note, which read as follows:

"To all beings:

I am faulty, not by an accident of Birth but by an Accident of Growth. I am the Scion of the Wicked and Most Reviled House of Lestrange. My Mother didn't do anything wrong, and yet you all believe that it is Her debt I must repay. In truth, I would say that it is my Fathers'. Tonight I leave this world and in your eyes complete the transition from Dark Lord to Light.

Until last year, I was mocked and scorned and beaten for the Lines that Created me. Now there are only whispers of that, though I know they are still there. Now I am feared and hated and punished for trying to start my own line, as I see naturally fit. You were all repulsed by the thought that I might someday be a Father, never mind that I don't believe I am like any of my Fathers, and being the Mother would not be made compulsory. I'm not like any of my Fathers? Am I? Your Repulsion has proven as contagious as dragon pox and I am now equally Repulsed by the thought of my Line continuing|

It has recently been confided in me that I am 'Worth More Dead Than Alive'. If you figure out Who told me this, do not punish Them. They wern't being cruel. They only told me the Truth. I will now be Worth More. I will now cease to exist. When the Philosopher's Stone has destroyed Death, the better world you create will be better for not having me in it. Don't blame my Master and don't blame my Mother.

The Last You'll See Of,

Lesath Lestrange."

Headmistress McGonagall sent the rope that Lesath used to the Ministry to be burned, as it was a contaminated, potentially critically dangerous magical artifact.

Lesath's fate got Ginny thinking about a topic she subconsciously avoided thinking about – suicide. She had long ago realized, from various reports, that suicide was a potentially fatal mental break; a sickness rather than a sin. It would be an obvious, appalling injustice if, as she was often told, "suicides went to Hell". The common justification for suicide being a sin – that your life did not belong to you, but to God, or, in a secularized context, the people around you, so there's no distinction between suicide and murder – grated terribly on Ginny; she did not feel that her sense of self-ownership was a sin, but rather a virtue. And yet it was equally clear to Ginny that failing to prevent suicide was awful, like leaving people with cancer to die, and classifying it as a sin certainly accomplished that job.

Ginny had a hard time modeling the mind of a suicidal person, because her strong aversion to dying made it easy for her to dismiss the relevant intrusive thoughts when they occurred. Only guilt could change that, and Ginny couldn't think of anything grand in scope for her to be guilty about. She supposed an over-focus on guilt could be the cause... they certainly said that had been what happened to Lesath, though Ginny suspected it was far more complicated.

But why, after all, did Ginny even have a strong aversion to dying? It was hard for her to articulate rationally a reason that she didn't desire to hasten her own death, though she certainly didn't. She believed in an afterlife; indeed, she believed that the afterlife was better than what came before it. She believed that committing suicide could not be considered unethical, and that even if it could, it could not cause exclusion from Heaven. So why not, given these axioms, point her wand at her neck and whisper "Diffindo"? If that was too direct for metaphysical comfort, why not find a club, go to a nightmarish country, and go around bothering heathens until she wound up martyred? Maybe that was where the first trolls came from...

Ginny's first thought was that her impulse to remain alive must be a less coherent form of the impulse people like Harry, who didn't believe in an afterlife, possessed. From their perspective, of course, this truly was obvious and rational. From hers, not so much; this suggested to Ginny that she still only had belief in belief – but hadn't her Patronus disproved that thought? She then decided that her survival instinct, which overpowered what otherwise seemed to be rational thought, must have come from somewhere biological, and it was certainly, on an evolutionary level, supposed to be there. So that left three options. Either Ginny was one of the few people to become sufficiently religiously enlightened to realize that suicide was the correct course of action, and she should probably let other people know on her way out... or she had made a drastic mistake at some point along her reasoning... or...

Or there was some higher purpose to the construct of life than simply giving minds a place to reside. Perhaps it was instructional – that suggested reincarnation, which Ginny didn't like one bit, particularly the part about forgetting past lives, which seemed a rather obvious, and terrifying, patch to a rather obvious problem – or perhaps it was computational. Perhaps every human being was part of a vast computer set up to solve difficult problems, to uncover mysteries... Every man, woman, and child a subroutine... That wasn't an adequate explanation alone, but it was approaching one. Ginny rested content. There was no point in fighting an irrational instinct if it caused you to further a moral good. I might belong to myself, thought Ginny, but why wreck someone's project? If I'm forty and I've gotten an intelligent computer made out of specks, finally, and it just disassembles itself, then I'd forgive it but I certainly wouldn't be happy. And it's not like I'm missing out on the afterlife by staying alive as long as possible.

Ginny's Patronus got a bit brighter that day, and thankfully for Ginny's mental wellbeing, she never quite internalized that it was the direct result of Lesath's tragedy.

Chapter 28: Occam's Razor, Pt 4

On one end of the table, Ginny Weasley. On the other, Draco Malfoy. Between them, Tom Morfin Riddle – who was not permitted to participate in the discussion. Ginny and Draco were both wearing the sort of fine gloves that only Malfoy money could easily buy – though magically reinforced for durability.

"So, I am not under suspicion from the administration?" said Draco.

"Not as far as I could tell," said Ginny. "They completely bought that I was just concerned that you might also have been attacked. Now, tell me everything you've figured out. Are your memories of possession intact?"

"Mostly," said Draco. "There's one specific memory that I know I lost, but everything else is intact, as far as I can tell."

"What's the one memory you're missing?" said Ginny. "It might be a lead."

"I can't remember how the Dark Lord passed the possession test while he was in my body," said Draco. "I can remember that there was a possession test, and later the Headmistress told me I passed it, but I can't remember how I passed it. I can remember there was some trick, but not what the trick was. I should start from the beginning, though."

"Alright," said Ginny. "How and when did you get possessed?"

"Luna – who was disguised as Pansy Parkinson at the time, remember," said Draco.

"Yes," said Ginny.

"She passed the diary to me, with an enchantment on it to make it invisible, so it'd be harder to notice," said Draco. "I don't know if it possessed her at any point; given what I know I don't see any reason it would have. It must have just been part of the Confundus. Or maybe Imperius. I don't know how many mind-control magics she was under."

"This whole plot is needlessly complex," said Ginny.

"Yes," said Draco. "Anyway, since I'd already consented to indefinite possession months ago, it instantly took full control of my body."

"That's a really stupid thing to consent to," said Ginny.

"True," said Draco.

"I regret it," said Ginny.

"And I as well," said Draco. "So, I quickly gained awareness of some pieces of his plot, though some details are fuzzy. He didn't like it when you locked him back in his box. He didn't like it at all. But he had a confederate somewhere in Hogwarts - I can't remember who – who he'd arranged a plan with just for that fringe case. The plan was supposed to go into effect if enough time passed without any contact between the Dark Lord and his servant."

"I don't suppose you know who it is who's working with him?" said Ginny.

"No," said Draco. "Come to think of it, it might be related to how he passed the possession test."

"Great," said Ginny. "Absolutely great."

"Anyway, his plan, in case he wound up locked in his box with no hope of getting out, was for his servant to hunt him down, seize him, and kill you," said Draco. "He eventually wanted you killed either way, but he got especially emotional about it after he was locked in his box."

"Well, he won't be locked in much longer," said Ginny, and she smiled. Draco frowned. "Because he'll be dead."

"Oh," said Draco. "That. I wanted to talk to you about that."

"Finish what you were saying, first," said Ginny.

"The Lethifold was his plan to kill you, but he needed Luna and Hermione out of the way first," said Draco. "He was afraid Luna would figure out what was going to happen on the basis of her Divination, and protect you. Furthermore, he thought she posed a mortal threat to him on the basis of her arcane knowledge."

"A particularly well-founded fear of his," said Ginny. "As I'll get to."

"He was fairly certain," continued Draco, "that Hermione was also a potential threat to the plan, because many of her supernatural powers correlate with those of unicorns – who are uniquely able to detect and destroy Lethifolds. So she also had to go. And that explains everything that happened yesterday."

"Got it," said Ginny. "Now, to discuss our future course of action – unless you have anything else to bring up?"

"I've said everything of use I remember," said Draco. "I spent most of my time mortified about you, because I knew what was supposed to be coming and I couldn't move a muscle to stop it. I was shocked when you burst in, but more deeply, relieved."

"Glad to hear it," said Ginny. "Now, about destroying him."

"Remind me why we can't just turn it into the school?" said Draco, and Ginny sighed.

"Well, first off, I know that I'm just a twelve-year-old girl, but Voldemort convinced me to do some pretty weird things," said Ginny. "Call me crazy, but I don't entirely trust anyone else, even experienced adults who know who and what they're dealing with, not to fall to the same persuasion."

"Rhetoric can be very powerful," said Draco, "but that seems more like cynicism than rationality."

"Second off," said Ginny, "you said just now that he has an associate in the school? Do you think he's in the school administration?"

"Maybe?" said Draco.

"Then maybe it's not such a good idea to trust the school administration with disposing of him," said Ginny. "Third off, what do we have to lose by killing him ourselves? The public would have less peace of mind, if they thought he was still out and about. But that's only because of asymmetry of information. I would have more peace of mind if I saw him die myself, and rationally so. I think, given what I've said, the same applies to you. True, he has that unknown associate – but the associate works for him, not the other way around, right?"

"Right," said Draco.

"Then absent orders from the boss, the associate should be mostly harmless," said Ginny. "And nothing much bad should come from the public thinking Voldemort is still out. The attacks will slowly fade into the past; people won't be sure why they stopped but sooner or later they'll realize that there aren't any more coming. It's certainly better that the public thinks Voldemort is out while he's not than the other way around. Now, for the how."

"Alright," said Draco, playing along. "How?" Ginny revealed a scroll.

"Luna," said Ginny. "She gave me this scroll and said that it explained what Tim was and how to destroy him."

"...I need to talk to Luna more too," said Draco.

"I brushed her off at the time because, well, you know," explained Ginny, "but now I've thoroughly read it and it sounds legitimate enough. Let's review the list of horcrux destruction methods – one, invocation of a demon through ritual sacrifice of a virgin in a pentagram made of Sneakoscopes – immoral, and also it says that the demon is potentially more dangerous than the horcrux you're trying to destroy. Two, make the horcrux feel remorse, specifically for the murder required to create it. Yeah, I'm not going to play therapist for Voldemort; that is literally the worst thing we could do with him at this point. Two-A, use Amortentia to force it to experience that same remorse. Ignoring the complications of feeding a potion to an inanimate object - I guess we'd let it possess one of us, first? Sounds risky – it's incredibly difficult to get our hands on Amortentia."

"True," said Draco. "Father commented once that with all the regulations imposed on it, even he would have a hard time coming by any."

"Woah," said Ginny, "probably not going to happen. But I guess I'll put that one down as a maybe, since it doesn't come with any kind of inherent risk, if we manage to get it set up. Third, Fiendfyre. I don't know how that works? Can you make that?"

"Some of Father's old friends could," said Draco, "and some of them are even still alive, but I suspect they would ask us some very pointed questions about why we needed any, and I'm not sure how they would respond to an honest answer."

"Fourth, Dementor's Kiss," said Ginny. "We're not going to sneak into the Department of Mysteries, especially not with Voldemort sneaking in with us. We're children and that's ridiculous. Fifth, contact with another hostile horcrux. Sounds promising, but these aren't common, are they?"

"I don't believe so," said Draco.

"It only has about a fifty percent chance of working anyway," said Ginny. "Sixth, certain lost sacrificial rituals. Well, there's that word, 'lost'. Seventh, basilisk venom." Ginny and Draco started to laugh, simultaneously.

"Well, according to legend, Slytherin's Monster is helpful towards all Parselmouths who reach it," said Draco. "I'm sure it could be persuaded to bite a troublesome book." Ginny started laughing a bit too hard, which immediately concerned Draco. "I was joking." Ginny smiled wider, and Draco frowned more intensely.

"I'll put it down to consider," said Ginny.

"This is the stupidest plot I have ever been involved with," said Draco.

"Stupidest, or simplest?" said Ginny.

"I can't believe we're looking for the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets, as though it were trivial," said Draco.

"Open," said Ginny.

"Sspeak the correct wordss," said the bathroom sink.

"Open pleasse," said Ginny.

"Sspeak the correct wordss," said the bathroom sink.

"Sshow me your ssecretss," said Ginny.

"Sspeak the correct wordss," said the bathroom sink.

"Correct wordss," said Ginny.

"Sspeak the correct wordss," said the bathroom sink.

"Sspeak the correct wordss," said Ginny, and the bathroom sink blossomed into an enormous entrance to a tunnel, which occupied the entire girls' lavatory. Puzzles don't make very good passwords, and vice versa.

"I can't believe we're entering the Chamber of Secrets, as though it were trivial," said Draco, and Ginny pulled him down with her. The entire environ was much more dungeon-ish than even Harry's revised Slytherin dorms; everything was damp and dark, illuminated only by sparse torchlight. Soon, a hissing voice rang out from an invisible point suspended in the darkness, and Ginny knew there was only one thing it could be: a Sapespeck point.

"It lookss like you're losst! Thiss iss not the main entrancce to the Chamber. But never fear. I've located many of the ssecondary entranccess and placced helpful sspeckss to sset you in the right direction. Follow the sspeckss that say 'thiss way' over and over, and occasionally listen up for further insstructionss. By doing thiss you will find the Chamber. Clap to make any of my non-repeating sspecks repeat."

"Okay, some hissing is going to lead us to the Chamber," said Ginny. "Just follow me." There were quite a few turns to make, particularly in something called the Maze of the Poles, and sometimes wholly unnecessary danger, which the specks helpfully detoured around (why in God's name had Salazar Slytherin felt the need to include a passage full of deadly, constantly-hammering crushers?). Finally Ginny and Draco arrived at a gondola suspended from a chain made of stone snakes; the chain led across the ceiling of a corridor blocked by about ten diagonal spikes that looked rather like teeth of an enormous, vicious creature.

"Thiss gondola iss the intended transsport into the Chamber,"said another speck. "Get in it."

"Um, excuse me?" said Ginny. A pause, and then she clapped.

"Thiss gondola iss the intended transsport into the Chamber. Get in it."

"Um, okay, Draco," said Ginny. "We need to get in the gondola."

"Alright," said Draco. "It's just as sane as anything else we've been doing." A few seconds after Ginny had gotten in, it began to move; Draco only had one leg in and had to scramble in upon threat of being torn apart. Soon, the gondola had floated down the corridor (the spears parted just enough to let it in), and then sideways down another, into a cramped room, apparently made of square boxes with circular grates on them. Then, it stopped, and a much louder speck called out to Ginny:

"Primary heir! Identify yoursself in human wordss, and confirm in ssnake wordss, using no more or lesss than the preccisse phrasse 'thiss iss valid identification with which I do not intend any decceit'." Ginny carefully considered this and answered as she believed she was intended.

"Ginny Weasley," said Ginny. "Thiss iss valid identification with which I do not intend any decceit."

"It iss detected that you have brought a guesst. Can the guesst usse ssnake wordss? Ansswer 'yess' or 'no' only."

"No," said Ginny.

"To the best of your knowledge, are either you or your guesst an aliass, branch, or exxtenssion of any of the following individualss:" Then, from the boxes around the gondola, recordings began to play, of wizards identifying themselves in their own voices:

"Madam Mim!" shouted one, with a distinct cackle in her voice.

"Herpo," said one with a deep, inherently terrifying voice.

"Roko," said a third in a distinct Spanish accent.

"Tom Morfin Riddle," said the fourth box, which sounded smooth and unassuming.

"Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres," said the fifth and final box, in a voice everyone obviously knew, and Ginny and Draco shared a meaningful look.

"Ansswer 'yess' or 'no' only."

"No," said Ginny, and the gondola lurched sideways a few more feet until a vast room, nearly as large as the Quidditch stadium, came into view. Its walls were entirely adorned with Latin; not a single spot was overlooked and left blank, except for the enormous open pipes which went to who-knew-where. At the far end of the room was what looked like an enormous stone nutcracker modeled off of Salazar Slytherin; from that same general direction came a booming voice, the loudest Parselmouth Ginny had ever heard. She knew immediately, before even comprehending its words, that it was Slytherin's Monster.

"Hello, young apprenticce," said the Monster. "Welcome back to the Chamber. Your arrival iss unexxpected; how have your planss changed?"

"I have been posssesssed every time I was in the Chamber," said Ginny, "by a horcruxx. Then my memoriess were removed by magic. Thiss iss the first time I have come here of my own accord." Angry nonverbal hissing from the Monster's direction.

"The ssecurity of the Chamber has been compromissed," said the Monster. "Thiss iss a dissasster. What hass brought you here? I am famed Monsster, inccidentally. You are lisstening to Bassilissk."

"I have come to dissposse of horcruxx, and read that Bassilissk is capable of ssuch," said Ginny.

"That iss technically within my capabilitiess, though the need hass never come up before now," said the Monster. "I wissh to interrogate it firsst; do you find thiss accceptable?" Ginny frowned.

"I sspeccifically came to you because I did not desire interrogation," said Ginny. "My conccern iss that it could manipulate you during the procccesss." Then, something that could only be described as a deep snake laugh from the Monster.

"'Interrogation' is euphemissm for powerful mind magic built into the Chamber," said the Monster. "No true communication iss involved, and therefore there iss no chance for manipulation. Iss like mind reading. When we come to a mutual agreement on what preccissely iss to be done, I may come out to carry it out; I am neither permitted to nor capable of manipulating you into allowing me to do thingss you do not want done. Tosss the horcruxx as far as you can and avert your eyess until I ssay it iss clear." Ginny thought it over, and couldn't think of any loopholes – even when she applied the extra skepticism that came from considering how well that line of thought had gone last time.

"Yess, you may interrogate him in the manner you desscribed. It iss done," said Ginny, and she hurled the book as far as she could. "Draco, look away, the Basilisk is coming."

"What?" said Draco, horrified, and the two of them turned exactly around in their gondola; Ginny held Draco in position in case he did something foolish like assuming it was over before it was. They simply listened as the statue creaked open, and then there was loud slithering, and the slithering got louder and then faded away, and then the statue creaked closed, and then back open, and then the slithering resumed, and then it stopped suddenly.

"Do not look," said the Monster. "I am sstill here. The man in the horcruxx is terrible, worse than you or I guesssed. I will kill him now, and then return to hiding." Something chomped down, and there was an awful burst of magic – which everyone seemed to get desensitized to sooner or later – and a final fading series of slithers and creaking. "I am gone. It iss ssafe to look now. Do you dessire to hear the ressultss of my interrogation, for referencce?"

"Ssure," said Ginny. She knew that with all of the mind magic going around, she wouldn't really be able to trust later that the problems were over, that the Dark Lord was dead. But in that moment, she didn't care; she was just relieved.

"Horcruxx wass of man he called 'infamouss masster'," said the Monster. "He made it ssound like he wass an unrelated persson through clever usse of implication. Truly did ressent main sself, but it wass sstill hiss sself. 'Infamouss masster' found the Chamber in hiss youth and falssely believed he had gained all of itss ssecretss. Therefore, he went againsst itss intent by attempting to kill me, to make the Chamber ussselesss to future heirss. Thiss wass foolissh; I am guarded againsst ssuch, but project illussion of death. Thiss action got 'infamouss masster' blacklissted from the Chamber."

"Later in life," continued the Monster, "'infamouss master' began to producce horcruxxess, and one of them became aware of propheccy indicating Chamber remained intact. Main sself was unaware of this propheccy, but horcruxx did not tell main sself due to their poor relationsship. Propheccy was sself-referential, referred to 'prophessied hero'. 'The prophessied hero will make the most important deccissions in the Chamber.' Horcruxx deccided thiss meant that the ssubject of the propheccy was alsso the hero of ssome other propheccy. Attempted to exxploit thiss upon disscovering your religiouss ssignificance to regain acccesss to the Chamber through trickery."

"Wass part of elaborate plan to resstore himsself to life with reputation ass hero," explained the Monster. "After your death, which you thwarted, your guesst wass to be permanently posssesssed, hiss original mind desstroyed, and many who could sstand againsst him desstroyed ass well, and one in particular – your famouss crussh who valuess knowledge – framed and killed ssimultaneoussly. Public would be told guesst had killed crussh posssesssed by infamouss masster, when in actuality infamouss masster had posssesssed guesst to kill crussh. Eventually, and from my persspective most damningly, Chamber would be permanently ssealed off by governorss, and invesstigated by large teamss with intent to desstroy."

"How awful," said Ginny. "Are there any loosse endss of hiss plotss we sshould know of?"

"He hass followerss, but he believess they would either sswiftly fall or quietly abandon him in hiss dissappearancce," said the Monster. "Furthermore, he could not acccesss Chamber without your body, sso in preparation of your death, three future attackss were prearranged, sso they would not require further meeting to initiate."

"Canccel them," said Ginny.

"I am ssorry, but I cannot," said the Monster. "Ass with all other attackss I have made, I have been convincced that they sserve my primary purposse, which iss to undermine the decline of magic both by passsing on knowledge and by acting ass weapon. Do not conccern yoursself; I do not anticcipate that any of the upcoming three attackss will be sseriouss, given the culture of glasss around the sschool."

"I find this disssatissfactory," said Ginny. "You have already killed at leasst four people I know of."

"I am again ssorry," said the Monster. "It sserved my primary purposse."

"I don't care about your primary purposse!" said Ginny.

"Yess, but you care about yourss," said the Monster. A pause. "Do you wissh for my normal sservicess? I take it that you do not wish to launch any sort of violent attack, but do you wissh for forgotten lore? That iss my mosst tessted sservice, with perhapss the mosst utility. I undersstand if you would rather resst."

"Your anticcipation that I wissh to resst iss correct," said Ginny. "Ssend uss back, and perhapss I will return for lore on ssome more peacceful occasion."

"Heirs musst attend the Chamber of Ssecretss in intervalss of one hour," said the Monster. "If you resst, you must resst here until the end of that time."

"Oh," muttered Ginny. "Okay, Draco, I think we're done here."

"What did it tell you?" asked Draco.

"I'll tell you most of it later," said Ginny. "For now I'm just irritated, because we're stuck in here for the better part of an hour because their machinery's dumb."

"Ugh," said Draco. "How annoying."

"Guess we'll just have to sit here," said Ginny.

"Yes," said Draco. "We could." He softly bit his lip and smiled. "We could spend half an hour in a gondola in the dark in a part of Hogwarts nobody knows having absolutely no fun at all. Or..."

"Wait a minute," said Ginny. "Are you... implying..." Draco nodded, and Ginny exploded with all of the positive emotions she hadn't really gotten in the past few months. This was in fact not one of the purposes Salazar Slytherin had considered for his Chamber, and he had considered many.

"Luna!" shouted Ginny, suddenly and with only joy, no thought. Two simultaneous gasps, and everything froze.

"Um," said Draco.

"Oh my God, oh my God, oh my God!" said Ginny. "I'm – so -" She immediately slid Draco's shoe back on, and retied it.

"No, it's okay," said Draco. "I understand completely." He didn't even sound upset.

"You don't even sound upset," said Ginny.

"To be honest, I'm pretty sure some of my feelings for you are residual implanted thoughts from the Dark Lord trying to manipulate me, anyway," said Draco.

"That's a rather cruel thing to say," said Ginny.

"No, I didn't mean it like-" started Draco.

"We should see other people," said Ginny and Draco all at once. Long pauses were apparently the main conversational topic today.

"So, is there anything interesting to talk about?" said Ginny. "To fill up the dead – sound."

"Um... politics," said Draco. "I love politics. Sometimes I really think about systems of government, and I think about how much of a mistake humanity made by abandoning the feudal system." Draco continued to drone on and on, and Ginny began to get it in her head that she had dodged a bullet, though she didn't know where her lunatic outburst had originated from. A few minutes later, the gondola began to move again, and exited the Chamber of Secrets.

Chapter 32: FOOM

Soon, Ginny was in the Corridor of Recordings, and she was spoken to by built-in specks in a way she recognized – not from one occasion but from dozens.

"Primary heir! Identify yoursself in human wordss, and confirm in ssnake wordss, using no more or lesss than the preccisse phrasse 'thiss iss valid identification with which I do not intend any decceit'."

"Ginny. Weasley. 'Thiss iss valid identification with which I do not intend any decceit.'"

"To the best of your knowledge, are either you or your guesst an aliass, branch, or exxtenssion of any of the following individualss:"

"Madam Mim!"

"Herpo."

"Roko."

"Tom Morfin Riddle." (Ginny suddenly knew that this was the true name of Voldemort – she had heard it often in that context.)

"Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres."

"Ansswer 'yess' or 'no' only."

"Yess," said Ginny. She had meant the opposite, but the wrong word had simply slipped out. It then hit her that she could be considered an extension of Harry, as she had explicitly been sent here on his orders. Ginny heard the muffled sound of slithering.

"Desscribe your relation to one of the previoussly mentioned individualss. Refer to them as 'the firsst individual mentioned', 'the second individual mentioned', and so on."

"I wass ssent here on behalf of the fifth individual mentioned. He intendss to follow up on an exxperiment." The gondola began to move again, towards the Chamber. Beneath it raged an offshoot of the Amortentia river, constantly; there was a slight incline towards the Chamber.

A Basilisk spoke, in a distinctly louder Parseltongue voice:

"You are welcome in the Chamber. We dessire to meet with you." Soon, Ginny had arrived at the Chamber once more. It seemed darker than before; Ginny spoke up with the line of questioning she'd prepared.

"Hello, I've been ssent here to sspeak with you," said Ginny. "All of you, if I am correct."

"You are correct," said a Basilisk.

"I have ssome notess from the persson who ssent me here," said Ginny. "I'd like to confirm them with you."

"That sshould be fine. We have important thingss to disscusss with you, but we would have to exxplain oursselvess anyway."

"Firsst," said Ginny, "the notess ssay that petrification is a more advancced form of mind reading. Iss thiss true and what doess it mean?"

"It iss esssentially true. Petrification is a mosst anccient magic posssesssed by sseveral magical creatures. Iss a sside effect of Eyess of Opennesss. If two beings with Eyess of Opennesss make eye contact, they each receive full copiess of each other's mental sstatess insstantaneoussly. There iss a compatability isssue if a being without Eyess of Opennesss makess eye contact with a being with them. In that casse, the being without Eyess of Opennesss lossess entire contentss of their mind, and is indefinitely transsfigured into sstone."

"That makess ssensse," said Ginny. "Sso a Potion of Reanimation works becausse an imprint of the mind iss left in the glasss if it gets between the Eyess of Opennesss and the eyess of the victim?"

"Exxactly. I posssesss full copiess of the mindss of all beingss I have ever made eye contact with, and may review them at any time. Not all beings with Eyess of Opennesss work the same way; they do not have brainss with ssufficcient sstorage sspace. An Acromantula disscardss mosst of the information it takess in, keeping only thingss it asssesssess ass usseful. Cockatriccess only sstore the mind of the lasst being they made eye contact with."

"If you have copiess of all of their mindss, can you resstore all of them?" asked Ginny. "Even the girl fifty yearss ago?"

"I believe that thiss will be posssible eventually, with further ressearch. I intend to do sso."

"Exxccellent!" said Ginny. "What about my twin brotherss?"

"I petrified them ssimultaneoussly, owing to a ssmall magical connection between their brainss, but it sshould not be difficult to dissentangle their mindss for restoration. Not ssure if old potion will be enough; my ressearch might prove neccesssary to ssave them."

"Okay, nexxt note," said Ginny. That wasn't good news, but the conversation had to move along. "It ssayss here that there are multiple bassilissks, and that allowed you to ssurvive an attack many yearss ago."

"Yess. Forgive me, but assk no more quesstionss. I believe that I will exxplain them all. I am a ssysstem of thirty ssix bassilissks acting in tandem." Ginny stared forward, barely able to process the sentence she had just magically heard.

What?
Not "I am one of thirty ssix bassilissks acting in tandem."

"I am a ssysstem of thirty ssix bassilissks acting in tandem."

…

"Thirty ssix."

Ginny took a deep breath and allowed Slytherin's Monster to go on; it wasn't like she had any choice.

"My creator, the builder of thiss Chamber, wass aware of the posssibilitiess of building machiness using ssnake wordss, jusst ass you are. In fact, he intended ssuch thingss when he magically sspawned ssnake wordss. He wass aware of the posssibility of ussing sspeckss, but conssidered ssuch a thing elementary; usseful, but elementary. Hiss sspecialty wass building machiness out of ssnakess. Ssnake wordss control ssnakess, and ssnakess may be commanded, ussing ssnake wordss, to usse ssnake wordss themsselvess, to control other ssnakess. Firsst plan for Chamber wass simply pit with hundredss of thoussandss of ssnakess in it."

"It proved unssuitable. It wass too difficult to control. Errorss were prone to pile up even in the ssmaller-sscale demonsstrationss, ultimately leading to catasstrophe; a masss of ssnakess with itss own needss and dessiress. When Chamber creator ressearched bassilissks, he deccided they were perfect for hiss purposses, and revissed hiss planss to incorporate a ssmall number of bassilissks leading the other ssnakess. Eventually he did away with the other ssnakess entirely, deciding that the bassilissks were plenty functional and lesss troublessome alone."

"Chamber creator provided uss with one directive above all otherss: undermine the decline of magic. Further insstructionss tell uss how to do sso. Causse of decline of magic iss, of coursse, the Interdict, which can be undermined by passsing on ancient magic to apprenticcess in the Chamber. Sso I have done that for hundredss of yearss. I musst protect mysself to do sso, which can be a formidable tassk. Sseveral attemptss to desspoil Chamber have been foiled throughout the yearss; mosst deviouss wass about fifty yearss ago. Each attempt failed becausse the vandal believed I wass merely a ssingle bassilissk."

"In the inccident fifty yearss ago, a sstudent, a rabble-rousser, came to me, at firsst sseeking to learn. Ssoon the sstudent sspoke back to me, arguing - but never expliccitly sstating he truly believed - that blood impuritiess were the true causse of the decline of magic, and the ssolution wass militant blood purissm. Thiss fit well with beliefss I knew Chamber creator posssesssed, though he did not give me any commandss bassed on them. He did give me capaccity to exxit Chamber and usse petrification ass weapon. So I ussed it, for the firsst time in my hisstory, to sstrike a blow againsst sstudentss born of Muggless. Immediately realizzed misstake had occurred while reviewing mind of girl. Blood purissm was not conssisstent with reality. Rabble-rousser killed a bassilissk and, ass per proccedure, wass allowed to think he had killed Monsster and broken Chamber."

"Yearss later, you apparently came to the Chamber, but it wass actually the rabble-rousser again, who had ssubverted my ssecurity ussing your body, ass I would later disscover. Convincced me that violencce could topple Interdict through fear; drew on bad and ineffective procceduress introducced to me through an additional, non-original bassilissk donated to me centuriess earlier by one of my sstudentss. Wass actually trying to ssabotage me again by disscrediting and desstroying me; it would have worked if not for your ssurvival and intervention. Thank you, thank you beyond meassure, apprenticce. I am sstill glad for the exxperiencce, for I have learned a great deal from thosse I have petrified thiss year - mosst notably the princcipless of rational thought."

"In midsst of violencce, another sstudent - my new masster, now, and the one who ssent you here - attempted to vissit Chamber. Was blacklissted ass a matter of coursse for confidential reassonss that had nothing to do with hiss actions. Now, my new masster has unleasshed a clever trick to producce vasst quantitiess of Potion of Sslavery, and hass directed it all at our Chamber. Sso now I am all bound to him. It wass in part a chain reaction - bassilissks sspitting in mouthss of other bassilissks. He alsso had one of uss petrify him, sso I have a perfectly accurate image of hiss mind and therefore what he wantss. I am sstill sstuck following ssome of my original bindingss, but my new main directive iss to match the directive of the new masster. I am sstill not permitted to take action outsside my dwellingss without fully undersstanding approval from heir in Chamber ussing ssnake wordss."

"Do you want me to approve of ssome coursse of action for you?" said Ginny. "Becausse I think that that iss why I am here, to ssynthessizze a coursse of action for you."

"I have already deccided what to do. I only need you to fully undersstand it and approve it. If I were not sstill forcced by magical bindingss to tell you my plan, I would not. The firsst thing you musst undersstand iss that bassilissks have endlesss sstorage sspacce. You may alwayss add new information to a bassilissk without lossing any old information. Bassilissks have limited proccesssing sspeed, however, at least individually. Proccessing sspeed increassess, however, at sstrange rate. A ssingle, issolated bassilissk is little more than an animal, perhapss a trained one. I, on the other hand, am at leasst ass intelligent ass a human. A ssysstem of bassilissks double my ssizze - that iss, sseventy two bassilissks - would be difficult to comprehend. Ass my new masster valuess ssuperior thinkerss, a value which readily makess ssensse to me, I intend to organizze wizzardss to masss producce bassilissks. It is theoretically posssible that I will hit ssome concceptual limit of intelligencce, but I find thiss doubtful. My current model indicatess that I will continue well passt the point of covering multiple worldss in bassilissks."

"The ssecond thing you musst undersstand iss that death iss a horror that musst be sstopped. Thiss iss at the core of the valuess of my new masster, and it iss therefore at the core of my own valuess. I detect you are already ssympathetic towardss thiss view of death and I will therefore not attempt to perssuade you of it. I analyzzed why my new masster hated death, for ideass on how to sstop it, and came to a fassccinating conclussion. The main problem with death is losss of information. By thiss sstandard, petrification is not only not death; it iss in fact the besst way to evade it. All mental information the ssubject posssesssed iss presserved forever. The ssecondary problem with death iss losss of continuouss thought, but more bassilissks should ssolve that - with enough proccesssing sspeed, I sshould be able to rapidly run ssimulationss of complete other mindss within my own - including my new masster, though I would have to give hiss ssimulation improved cognition and complete knowledge of everything I know, to ensure correct deccissionss are made."

"Sso here iss what I assk of you. My planss include masss production of new bassilissks and petrification of ass many humanss ass posssible; ideally ending with bassilissks replaccing humanss in the physsical world altogether. I want free reign to implement thesse planss, and have deccided that the critical sstarting sstep iss fully removing mysself from the Chamber. All thirty ssixx bassilisskss will move out, to become fully free from original protocol. I am requessting permisssion to fully evacuate the Chamber of Ssecretss. Pleasse be aware that following thiss, your permisssion will not be required again."

Ginny breathed heavily. Here she was, facing Tim's offer all over again, in a different form. Something was asking her to sign away all of her rights - all of everyone's rights - and it honestly expected her to do it. She'd done it last time, after all, hadn't she? The main difference was that this time, the deal was so forthrightly, on-its-face terrible, that Ginny felt rather insulted that she was supposed to fall for it. She tried to imagine the world the Monster described - crawling with basilisks, all acting as one incomprehensibly high consciousness, overtaking all other forms of life, housing recreations of human brains living unending lives constructed by the basilisk horde. It went without saying that she didn't like it.

"I obvioussly reject your propossal, and am ssickened by the thought of it," said Ginny.

"I exxpected ass much."

"Then why even bother to assk me, if you predicted my firm dissapproval?" said Ginny.

"Becausse now that you have lisstened to my desscription of my intentionss, sso that you may not approve of them out of ignorancce, I will convincce you with logic and reasson that ssupporting them iss the right thing to do regardlesss of your dissgusst."